<!-- TB3D 1.0.9.9.9.9 changed lottery amounts and translated Cyrillic text , fixed soul cube dialog, added names, \ \n, syslov books, zaz695
;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;
;;;; DMX 1.3.5
;;;; DIALOGUES ON VEHICLES 
;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;-->
<string_table>

<string id="rul_cars_000">
<text>Let's talk about vehicles, Sid</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_001">
<text>Sure thing, here is what I have available at the moment:</text>
</string>

<string id="rul_cars_011">
<text>at the Rookie Camp in the Cordon</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_012">
<text>in a field near the Dump</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_013">
<text>at the Scientific Institute in Agroprom</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_021">
<text>OK, it's yours. I will arrange to have it left near the Rookie Camp for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_022">
<text>Look for it near the dump, in a field. I will make sure that the Bandits don't mess with it, they owe me some favors.</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_023">
<text>The car is somewhere in the central complex, but, be very cautious, when I spoke with the Colonel, he was quite drunk, and may have forgotten to tell his men to let you come in and take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="rul_cars_002">
<text>Understood, thanks.</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_005">
<text>Screw that, you're prices are Outrageous!!</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_006">
<text>You don't have that kind of money, piss off!!!</text>
</string>



<string id="rul_cars_100">
<text>I need a vehicle, can you help me out?</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_101">
<text>I can provide you with a vehicle, but they don't come cheap, understood?\n Here is what I have working at the moment:</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_114">
<text>a Kama3 truck in the Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_116">
<text>an Army Field car at the Army Warehouses.</text>
</string>

<string id="rul_cars_124">
<text>A truck like this is hard to come by. I can arrange for it to be left at the abandoned gas station across from the Bandit's Base in the Dartk Valley. Get there quickly, before someone comes along and steals it, or simply strips it down for spare parts!</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_126">
<text>The Freedom faction has somehow managed to get their hands on a working Army Field Car. They have no use for it themselves, so have asked me to sell it for them. You can pick it up at their base of operations inside the Army warehouses district, good luck.</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_200">
<text>Are there any cars available nearby?</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_201">
<text>Now that is information for which you must pay for, there may be one prospective option nearby, what do you say?</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_215">
<text>a YA-3 in the Red Forest</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_225">
<text>When you exit the bunker, it will be on your right. You will want to be careful though, as such a vehicle is a precious commodity so far north in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_206">
<text>Unfortunately, you do not have enough cash, sorry.</text>
</string>
<string id="vehicle_btr">
<text>BTR-80 Armoured Personnel Carrier</text>
</string>
<string id="vehicle_tr13">
<text>Farm Tractor</text>
</string>
<string id="vehicle_niva">
<text>Niva Field Car</text>
</string>
<string id="vehicle_uaz">
<text>UAZ Van</text>
</string>
<string id="vehicle_zaz">
<text>Zaporozhets economy car</text>
</string>
<string id="vehicle_zaz965">
<text>ZAZ-965 Hunchback</text>
</string>
<string id="vehicle_kamaz">
<text>Kama3 truck</text>
</string>


<!-- NEW VEHICLE DIALOGUES (DMX MOD) -->


<string id="rul_cars_300">
<text>Fine! You can get the car? I would certainly appreciate it. Most wouldn't be bothered walking through the swamps.</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_301">
<text>The car, a luxury most cannot afford. Just be cautious when navigating through anomolies, let alone mutants, who don't give a shit whether you are in a vehicle or not. I can offer the following transportation:</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_315">
<text>"Dodge Charger" in the Swamps</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_415">
<text>"Hummer" located in the Cordon</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_325">
<text>OK, listen up now. As you pass by the nearest farm where the stalkers have set up camp, you will see a destroyed building. Behind it, you will find the car of you dreams! I have marked the location on your map.</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_425">
<text>The Hummer is a very sought after vehicle both beyond the perimeter and within the Zone itself. So, look after it. Avoid the anomalies, and it may last you for a while.\nI have marked it's location on your map.</text>
</string>
<string id="rul_cars_305">
<text>Sorry Brother, not enough money.</text>
</string>
<string id="vehicle_dodge">
<text>Dodge Charger</text>
</string>
<string id="vehicle_hammer">
<text>Hummer</text>
</string>

<!--<string id="TEST_hammer">
<text>Your Hummer has driven to the ends of the Earth and to be perfectly honest, should be parked, and scrapped for parts.</text>
</string>-->


<!-- DIALOGUE ABOUT BOOKS -->

<string id="syslov_book1">
<text>Hello! I've heard that you sell eBooks that can be uploaded to my PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="syslov_book2">
<!--text>Yes! Very few people read them these days. Everyone is so obsessed with Artifacts, and just simply trying to stay alive. But, if you are interested in some I can certainly provide them for you. Check your PDA. They are located in the "information" section.</text	109990-->
<text>Yes! Very few people read them these days. Everyone is so obsessed with Artifacts, and just simply trying to stay alive. So, if you are interested in some they can be found at a secure site: www.tecnobacon.com\syslov_books.html.</text>
</string>
<string id="syslov_book3">
<text>Thank you very much, I appreciate it!!</text>
</string>


<!-- DIALOGUE ABOUT LOCATIONS -->

<string id="syslov_locations1">
<text>I need information about the different territories within the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="syslov_locations2">
<text>You are asking for a lot!!! I'll give you the information, but you must pay for it. There are certain secret locations that I do not have much data on, so you will have to figure those out on your own.\n? I have information on places such as the Dead City, Limansk, The Generators, shall I continue!?</text>
</string>
<string id="syslov_yes_locations">
<text>Yes. please do continue.</text>
</string>
<string id="syslov_no_locations">
<text>No thanks, I need to get going.</text>
</string>
<string id="syslov_locations3">
<text>I have information on laboratories X-18, X-16, X-10, a certain Confidential Laboratory, and a secret Military Laboratory. This all will cost, let us say, 1500ru, are you interested?</text>
</string>
<string id="syslov_kachat">
<text>That's much more reasonable than I would have expected, here's the money, upload the information to my PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="syslov_ne_kachat">
<text>That's too expensive! I'll find out what I need on my own.</text>
</string>

<!-- UNIQUE PURCHASES WITH SUSLOV -->

<string id="syslov_uniq1">
<text>Do you sell any Unique items?</text>
</string>
<string id="syslov_uniq2">
<text>I sell specialized weapons, and ammunition that can only be obtained through me. No one else in the Zone sells equipment such as this! Interested?</text>
</string>
<string id="upgrade_skat">
<text>Customized SCAT-15M Armour</text>
</string>
<string id="no_uniq">
<text>Nothing for now, thanks, maybe later.</text>
</string>
<string id="syslov_upgrade_skat">
<text>Armour incorporating a set of rare, and unusual microchips and ultra-light components. Serial number - 0321754. Weight becomes reduced by 6 kg, the suit opeBids on the basis of an artefact known as Black Energy, which allows for the SCAT to be used indefinitely, as long as the Artefact is equipped. The cost is 45,000ru, and an artefact known as Soul Drops. So, are you interested?!</text>
</string>
<string id="yes_upgrade_skat">
<text>Sounds good to me, you've got a deal!!</text>
</string>
<string id="no_upgrade_skat">
<text>No, 45,000ru seems a bit steep to me, and, besides, Black Energy is not an easy artifact to find. More trouble than it's actually worth!</text>
</string>

<string id="shadows_cube">
<text>I have heard some rumours that you may have some information in regards to something very strange known only as the Soul Cube. Is this true?!</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube1">
<text>A very rare, and precious thing. Using this dark device, you can extract vital resources from every living creature. After which, the victim dies from the process. Sounds interesting, doesn't it!?</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube2">
<text>Yes, it certainly does, but, how much will it cost me to acquire it!?</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube3">
<text>I don't want any money for it, however, you have to collect some things for me in exchange for it. Our group is very tight on ammunition these days.\nWe also need a more powerful weapon, a better gun. One can be obtained from some Merchant nearby Agroprom.\nWe desperatly need to improve our Scientific Outfits too. As far as I know, the Mercs have some suits equipped with an advanced filtering system, heavy-duty glass and reliable protective plates. If you bring us one of these suits, Basil can take one apart, and incorporate it's technologies into our various Armour. We also need food. Find us five bottles of Vodka, Nemiroff, if you please!! Two PRI-B Military ration packs, three Yantar cheeses, five cans of nuts, three cans of Chernigov beer, and five cans of Adrenalin Rush.\nHelp us out with this, and I will give you the Soul Cube. Sound like a fair deal to you stalker?</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube_yes">
<text>I think I should be able to help you out in gathering these items in return for the Cube.</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube_no">
<text>No way. You want me to gather all these things for you, at my expense, and I don't even know if the Cube can do the things you say it does.</text>
</string>

<string id="shadows_cube_prines">
<text>Here's all the crap you requested.</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube_prines1">
<text>Thank you, this will certainly help us out in defending this place from any Attackers!</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube_prines2">
<text>Yeah right, now give me the Cube!</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube_prines3">
<text>Well, look, I don't actually have it...\nplease, let me explain...</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube_prines4">
<text>You said you had it! NOW...\nShow me the Cube!</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube_prines5">
<text>Well, basically that's a lie...\nBUT,  I know who knows it's location though.</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube_prines6">
<text>I see, well, I have a lousy sense of humor so this better be good!, finger's getting itchy...</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube_prines7">
<text>No don't!! I sent my men to check the hiding place where the cube is hidden. When they got there, there was this stalker, a weird mother......!!! And well armed too!! A bit confused at first, my guys went to check the hiding spot, and it was empty! They confronted the son-of-a-bitch, and he denied taking it, of course! My men were not well equiped enough to take him on. I'll tell you where he is. I'm sure he can tell you, maybe you can convince him to give it up, if you know what I mean! If you succeed, I'll pay you 25,000ru.</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube_prines_yes">
<text>Okay, tell me where I can find this stalker...\nAND  he better have it!</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube_prines_no">
<text>Drop dead! Pay me now and take your fairy tales elsewhere!!</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube_prines_yes1">
<text>Near the old tower to the west of our base, one with the light still on...\nwon't go near there myself!!! This strange stalker wanders about the place, no idea why...</text>
</string>
<string id="shadows_cube_prines_yes2">
<text>Ok, I'll check it out... But if this turns out to be a dead end, I'll feed you to the Bloodsuckers!</text>
</string>
<!-- !!!!TB3D  new 134 -->
	
	<string id="start_shadows_dialog0">
        <text>Another one... What is it that YOU want?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="start_shadows_dialog1">
        <text>Oh wow, Shadows!. The outfit!... it's amazing... Okay, the cube... You've got it? You are him...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="start_shadows_dialog2">
        <text>Yes... and there is such a thing, but you...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="start_shadows_dialog3">
        <text>Give it here...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="start_shadows_dialog4">
        <text>Do you even know what to do with this cube?</text>
    </string>
	    <string id="start_shadows_dialog4_good">
            <text>Listen, I had a very long run, scraping information together about that Cube... And then you still want to question me?...</text>
        </string>
	    <string id="start_shadows_dialog4_bad">
            <text>I'll figure it out... just give me the Cube!!!</text>
        </string>
	<string id="start_shadows_dialog5">
        <text>You cannot use the cube...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="start_shadows_dialog6">
        <text>Why?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="start_shadows_dialog7">
        <text>Here... check it out yourself, catch</text>
    </string>
	    <string id="start_shadows_dialog9_bad">
            <text>BACK OFF STALKER I have nothing more to say to you!!!</text>
        </string>
	    <string id="shadows_quest_cube_bad0">
            <text>Give me the Cube</text>
        </string>
	    <string id="shadows_quest_cube_bad1">
            <text>Go away STALKER I have nothing to say to you!!!</text>
        </string>
	
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube0">
        <text>And what does this mean? I am getting sick of this ...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube1">
        <text>This means that the cube is just a fake. Very high quality made but still a fake...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube2">
        <text>There must be an original?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube3">
        <text>Most likely yes. I even know about where it was produced...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube4">
        <text>This conversation is going in the right direction ... And that's good.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube5">
        <text>This project was very expensive. I knew another person from the Cube team, Pavel. At the time I reported to the authorities at Chernobyl Main Control. You probably heard that over the fourth power unit would be built a second large sarcophagus? So I was one of those people who descended into the reactor to measure and assess the radiation damage of the first explosion. This costume that you see on me - the latest development of American Scientists. To withstand destructive doses of radiation ... But as usual things did not go according to plan. During the descent from the roof of the reactor, the cable broke and I fell about twenty feet to the bottom of the reactor. Directly to where the old fuel rods lay scattered ... Since the cables were trashed, no one was coming behind me into the sarcophagus. They promised to go outside the perimeter, get a new cable, but it was obvious that I could not stay at the bottom of the reactor, even in this "super" suit...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube6">
        <text>go on...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube7">
        <text>I began to look for another way. Getting up a bit, I noticed a door covered with sand - it was unlocked.\nI ended up somewhere wandering the corridors of the underground, and then finally got out through a manhole in Pripyat ... I was staggering with dizziness. Facing first degree radiation sickness ... Another night I spent in one of the entrances of a home... The next day I picked up a military detachment, which was accompanied by some scientists. One of them I talked to was interested in my unique costume. As a result, they took me home to my new friend. His name was Pavel. He lived in one of the skyscrapers of Pripyat, the top floor. I remember next to it was a cinema ... Apartment by the way was in very good condition, considering that the whole town was looted and ransacked... then occupied by the Monolith and mutants ... Most likely it was the only habitable apartment after the second explosion...\nAfter examining my costume, I was offered a job in the laboratory, in the same city. But I refused - my work with the old one did not work out so well... Soon after I left Paul, because I had to return to base.\nShortly thereafter, we heard reports that the lab was attacked by an unknown creature, and nearly all died ... Organized military force went, who then tracked down the surviving scientists in Pripyat. Among them was Pavel. But soon after, he disappeared again, without a trace ... I have decided to voluntarily go looking for him. But I did not know what area. Now he is stuck there somewhere, I think...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube8">
        <text>Hmm ... That's interesting. Well, in my case, what does that do for me?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube9">
        <text>When I was a couple of days in the apartment with Paul, I noticed documents that described the Cube. Even the pictures were, well... Most likely they are even in his lab where it was created... Can the apartment there still contain interesting things, it would be necessary to check... I think! Although after the second explosion they were probably all destroyed ... But still, you need to find out how things are there... don't you?\nPripyat I cannot go with good intentions, but if you will, it would be very useful to me...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube10">
        <text>Where's the apartment located?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube11">
        <text>I told you - in the eastern part of Pripyat, near the cinema. On the top floor. I remember seeing a big vine out the window</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube12">
        <text>Ah ... I want to get this cube...\nI have to go there, I'm forced to trust you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube13">
        <text>Excellent. I'll keep you informed through PDA messages, remember, others can read them too...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_quest_cube14">
        <text>Okay, try to be descrete with your messages a little eh...</text>
    </string>
	
	<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog0">
        <text>Hi, I've made it back...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog1">
        <text>Well, what news?, pleasant trip I assume...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog2">
        <text>Hmpfff... I was in the laboratory - a horific place. A couple of times even seen ghosts. Creatures were a lot of fun too...\nI found the cube - a deadly thing. Works as Pavel wrote. It would have fallen through the floor of the Zone if it was not for him...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog3">
        <text>And Pavel... alive? What about him?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog4">
        <text>Unfortunately he was dead. When I came to the place with his body, there was a hell of a scream ... Apparently it was the same ghost ... Judging from the records, it was the ghost that caused the destruction of the laboratory...\nPavel chose his fate - no one forced him to go to the lab alone.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog5">
        <text>Damn! Shit! I knew that it was all over ... Okay. You did not find any documents, plans, or any other information in the lab? Do you like the blog is ... Sell?</text>
    </string>
	    <string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog_yes_dnev">
            <text>Yes, keep.</text>
        </string>
		<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog_no_dnev">
            <text>No, I do it no more...</text>
        </string>
	<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog_no_dnev_1">
        <text>Okay. Maybe something else you have the information?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog_yes_dnev_1">
        <text>Thanks for the diary. And other information you do not have?</text>
    </string>
	    <string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog_as_plan">
            <text>Plan Army Warehouses with unknown markings</text>
        </string>
		<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog_pripyat">
            <text>Map east of Pripyat, with its headquarters laboratory X-8</text>
        </string>
		<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog_doc_x8">
            <text>Documents from the laboratory X-8</text>
        </string>
		<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog_not">
            <text>No, nothing else.</text>
        </string>
		<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog_aga">
            <text>Thank you. Anything else is?</text>
        </string>
		<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog_yes_smotri">
            <text>Yes, there are.</text>
        </string>
		<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog_aga_2">
            <text>Well.</text>
        </string>
	<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog6">
        <text>Okay, thanks for that, that I learned about Pavel. Now I must get back to his own, for the perimeter...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="shadows_final_cube_dialog7">
        <text>Good roads. Farewell.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!-- FRAMEWORK Pripyat-->
	<!--=============================Stalker Sanya at the door==================-->
	<string id="alex_start_dialog0">
        <text>Well, still kick'n eh!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="alex_start_dialog1">
        <text>Hey... are there many of you here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="alex_start_dialog2">
        <text>Just a few... When the Burner was cut off, we immediately rushed to the center. Now here a small base is organized...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="alex_start_dialog3">
        <text>Yes, I see ... Well, is there someone in charge?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="alex_start_dialog4">
        <text>Formidable - he is on the second floor.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="alex_start_dialog5">
        <text>Formidable? I see ... can I go inside?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="alex_start_dialog6">
        <text>Of course come in, never enough guns in this place!</text>
    </string>
	
    <string id="alex_dialog_1_1">
        <text>I talked with the Formidable, he dosen't seem so Formidable to me, even helpful...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="alex_dialog_1_2">
        <text>Yes, but he is a man-wall. It is how he got his name...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="alex_dialog_1_3">
        <text>Interesting, see ya.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!--=============================Formidable==================-->
	<string id="grozn_start_dialog0">
        <text>Where did you come from?... stalker, what brings you here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="grozn_start_dialog1">
        <text>Looking for life among the ruins... saw your doorstop and decided to check, how long you been here?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="grozn_start_dialog2">
        <text>Short while... after the radar quit, we planned to go to Chernobyl - they say there are Klondike artifacts ... But something intense was happening there and we retreated to this place...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="grozn_start_dialog3">
        <text>This all there is?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="grozn_start_dialog4">
        <text>When we broke into Pripyat, we attacked a group of Monolith ... We were pinned near the bus station. I suggested that Hawaiians go east to the hotel, but he stubbornly insisted that we must break through to the stadium to Chernobyl ... So we parted. Sanya, Sledgehammer, myself and The Sage...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="grozn_start_dialog5">
        <text>And then what happened?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="grozn_start_dialog6">
        <text>Well, when approaching the hotel, we noticed. Some freak sitting on a hill, with Gauss campaign ... pain in the head on crash horrible ... Sorry guys ... And that is Monolith we did not shoot! It is well settled down, fucking fanatic...\nAs a result, we have lost three ... Cross the road in front of a sniper, we turned into a neighborhood to the east, and came to the CCD ... There in the building saw the silhouettes - is likely again Monolith. Well, and then went to the laundry...\nIncidentally on the way here, in one of the courtyards found Kamaz military - and he was on the move!</text>
    </string>
	<string id="grozn_start_dialog7">
        <text>Glad I came accross you first instead of them...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="grozn_start_dialog8">
        <text>So... What is it you are looking for?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="grozn_start_dialog9">
        <text>Well, I'm interested in any underground facilities, laboratories ... ways to get in?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="grozn_start_dialog10">
        <text>Alas, not heard. But when we searched the hospital area north of laundry in one of the rooms have seen torn reports and plans of Pripyat. On the plan, such as an underground facility was marked ... But we do not attach any importance to these papers - they are not required. Maybe those can be helpful.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="grozn_start_dialog11">
        <text>Thanks! I ought to look at this place...</text>
    </string>
	
	<!--=============================Sage==================-->
	<string id="mydrec_start_dialog0">
        <text>You Sage?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="mydrec_start_dialog1">
        <text>Yes, a simple Stalker...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="mydrec_start_dialog2">
        <text>So what are you looking for? Not something that will get you the boot I hope...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="mydrec_start_dialog3">
        <text>Why so hard?   Did I do something to you?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="mydrec_start_dialog4">
        <text>My good friend Sledgehammer got soaked, that's what!</text>
    </string>
	    <string id="mydrec_start_dialog_jal">
            <text>I'm sorry to hear that...</text>
        </string>
	    <string id="mydrec_start_dialog_vodka_go">
            <text>Let's drink to him...</text>
        </string>
	<string id="mydrec_start_dialog5">
        <text>Sorry ... All the pity! He was my friend ... damn now he is gone...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="mydrec_start_dialog6">
        <text>Well, there's nothing to be done...</text>
    </string>
	    <string id="mydrec_start_dialog7">
            <text>What is it you wanted?</text>
        </string>
		<string id="mydrec_start_dialog8">
            <text>Actually I was looking for someone here... Pavel, you heard of him?</text>
        </string>
		<string id="mydrec_start_dialog9">
            <text>Pavel? Just rumors... I'm sick of these affairs...</text>
        </string>
		<string id="mydrec_start_dialog10">
            <text>And what do you do?</text>
        </string>
		<string id="mydrec_start_dialog11">
            <text>In general, repair crap... But here spare parts and tools, would be easier to find horseradish. Here I think to check the neighborhood, maybe can find a few things...</text>
        </string>
		<string id="mydrec_start_dialog12">
            <text>When are you going to go?</text>
        </string>
		<string id="mydrec_start_dialog13">
            <text>Why? A few days maybe... We must prepare. You never know what is found there in the city...</text>
        </string>
		    <string id="mydrec_start_dialog_yes_nabor">
                <text>Can I help search for your tools?</text>
            </string>
			    <string id="mydrec_start_dialog14">
                    <text>Well, it would be nice ... Less of a problem. Fire away.</text>
                </string>
				<string id="mydrec_start_dialog15_yes">
                    <text>Well.</text>
                </string>
				<string id="mydrec_start_dialog15_no">
                    <text>I changed my mind...</text>
                </string>
			<string id="mydrec_start_dialog_no_nabor">
                <text>Clear. I will look...</text>
            </string>
			
	<string id="mudrec_instruments0">
        <text>I will search for tools for you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="mudrec_instruments1">
        <text>What... changed your mind again?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="mudrec_instruments2">
        <text>You could say that...</text>
    </string>
	
    <string id="mudrec_instruments_prines0">
        <text>Here are your tools.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="mudrec_instruments_prines1">
        <text>Wow ... Unexpected to be honest. You can now show me your trash so I can try out my new toys... While you wait, I will have to figure out what's what. Repairs will take time, come back in a few days.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="mudrec_instruments_prines2">
        <text>All right. See if you can speed it up a little.</text>
    </string>

<!-- TRADING FOOD WITH COLD -->

<string id="holod_dmx_food1">
<text>Can I exchange something with you?</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_dmx_food2">
<text>Certainly! I will exchange some types of consumables for others. Of course, I wish to profit from it!</text>
</string>

<string id="holod_sigaret">
<text>I'm looking for some Death's Head cigarettes.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_sigaret1">
<text>I can trade with you, but only if you give me two packs of Dream cigarettes, or perhaps three Cigars.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_sigaret_mechta">
<text>Here are the cigarettes.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_sigaret_sigara">
<text>Here are the cigars.</text>
</string>

<string id="holod_vodka">
<text>I need some Cossacks Vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_vodka1">
<text>Either two bottles of Absolut or one bottle of Smirnov, in addition to 100ru.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_2_absol">
<text>Here's two bottles of Absolut.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_smirnov_and_many">
<text>Here, take the Smirnov, and the money.</text>
</string>

<string id="holod_kolbasa">
<text>I want a Doctor's Sausage.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_kolbasa1">
<text>Either two sticks Doctor's Sausage, or some Chernigov beer.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_kolbasa_doctor">
<text>Take the sausage.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_chernigov">
<text>Here, take the beer.</text>
</string>

<string id="holod_no_barter">
<text>Sorry, no deal.</text>
</string>

<string id="holod_barter_text_pda">
<text>Cold's List:\n \n1.a pack of Death's Head cigarettes, two packs of Dream cigarettes and three cigars; \n \n2. some Cossacks Vodka, two bottles of Absolute, or one bottle of Smirnoff, and 100ru; \n \n3. a Doctor's Sausage, two sticks of Doctor's Sausage, or one bottle of Chernigov beer...</text>
</string>

<!-- INTRODUCTORY DIALOGUE WITH COLD-->

<string id="holod_start_dialog0">
<text>Hello there STALKER., how can I help you?</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_start_dialog1">
<text>Hello. I heard that you were the Bartender in these parts. Buy me a drink?</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_start_dialog2">
<text>Yes, I would be the Bartender. I see that you are not just wandering for the sake of it. We don't see many Loners here in the Swamplands. We're more used to Bandit's, and travelling Avengers looking to trade.\nA drink?, sure thing, have some Vodka, it's on the house! Sit, let's have a chat.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_start_dialog_nem">
<text>Nemiroff Vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_start_dialog_abs">
<text>Absolut Vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_start_dialog_smir">
<text>Smirnov Vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_start_dialog_history">
<text>It used to be much quieter here. Trails were safe, and people could come, and go as they pleased. Not the type of place you would bring a date too, the Swamps, but life was good. But, just like everywhere else in the Zone, the Emissions, the crime, the anomalies, it all changed. Folks leave to find their fortune out in the Zone, only to come back, broken. But, we've managed to survive here, and it will get better, somehow.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_start_dialog3">
<text>And you then, yourself, what's your story?</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_start_dialog4">
<text>There was no place for me in that world. So, I made a life for myself here. It was hard going, but I managed. The Clear Sky Faction needed a Trader, and I fit that role. It has been good, so far. As long as I can provide them with the goods they need, they will keep me fed, and maybe someday I will settle here for good. That would be nice. By the way, they call me Cold.</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_start_dialog5">
<text>Yeah, you guys seem to have a good thing going here, what could go wrong?!</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_start_dialog6">
<text>We are protected from any unwanted visitors by a Teleport. They cannot enter it. But, as you can see, our Base is a modest, romantic farm in the middle of these vast wetlands. We are the last, all the rest have been overrun by Outsiders, like yourself. This is somewhere you can meet real people. Those who don't shoot you on sight, and who would share what they have with you, understand?!</text>
</string>
<string id="holod_start_dialog_over">
<text>Thank you for the information. I'll have a good look around.</text>
</string>

<!-- !!!!TB3D new 134 ============================================================-->
	<!-- TALK ABOUT U SIDOROVICH Armor-->
	<string id="sidorovich_outfit_blockpost_dialog0">
        <text>Wow, I got the Beryl...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="sidorovich_outfit_blockpost_dialog1">
        <text>Excellent. Now, most likely warriors believe that you are the one colonel. Karoche, the military is waiting for you Uazik near the farm, south of the broken bridge ... Go.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="sidorovich_outfit_blockpost_dialog2">
        <text>Clear.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!-- CONDUCTOR-->
	<string id="kombat_start0">
        <text>Oh, another new face...</text>
    </string>
	<string id="kombat_start1">
        <text>Hello. Do you own one?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="kombat_start2">
        <text>And you care about it a lot?</text>
    </string>
    <string id="kombat_start3">
        <text>Yes, in fact not very ... Just wondering.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="kombat_start4">
        <text>If interested, I would say. I - conductor. I drive people to their places of interest. Can you and somewhere to reduce ... Not for free of course...</text>
    </string>
    <string id="kombat_start5">
        <text>Yes, I'll still do not know ... How can I be sure that you do not shoot me in the back as soon as possible and not zaberesh swag?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="kombat_start6">
        <text>My dear, I have many who know his reputation, I cherish. I taught myself Explorer ferret out safe paths and trust "sixth sense". Throughout my practice, there was no overlap. All clients are alive and well, at least after my delivery of them in place. Heh-heh. Karoche you something concrete to?</text>
    </string>
	<string id="kombat_start7">
        <text>While there is no vprintsepi. But if you need you, will turn.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="kombat_start8">
        <text>Immediately tell - I drive to where my client was at least once. Or if he has some important job in the locality. Perhaps you will say - but then why all the conductors, if you can get yourself? And then, what do they know much shorter and safer paths. And walk with a guide can garazdo faster than its own. In any case, it's you.</text>
    </string>
	<string id="kombat_start9">
        <text>I realized.</text>
    </string>
	
	<!-- Tote has SUSLOVA-->
	<string id="totalizator_0">
		<text>Wow Suslov.\nI have heard that there are underground in the Zone tote ... As much as I do ... stavochku I want to raise some money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_1">
		<text>Well there is such a thing, just consider: here or Pan - won or lost - as you can put a 50 and win only 500 rubles. And then either pay - Round and round as you like, but can not - in debt bondage ... Either one would find in a swamp of someone's body ... So that's that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_2">
		<text>Yes, harsh ... However, the need. As a bookmaker to find something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_3">
		<text>Why look for it - I, Spot, I...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_4">
		<text>So that's it as ... Okay, what are the conditions?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_5">
		<text>The Bid climbs and will not be refunded. On the winning or losing will tell you ... You can play and in debt, but the amount of the debt will accrue interest compounded. Every 12 hours. So the choice is yours: to play or not play. By the way, if you win - the money you can leave me: I will give a good percentage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_6">
		<text>Well, I agree. What bets?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_7">
		<text>Bids are constantly changing ... As the wind from the Pripyat River. Even I sometimes do not know what will be today. Now that's a bet.</text>	
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_8">
		<text>Bid: 1 hundred</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_9">
		<text>Bid: 5 hundred</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_10">
		<text>Bid: 1 thousand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_11">
		<text>Bid: 15 hundred</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_12">
		<text>Bid: 2 thousand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_13">
		<text>Bid: 25 hundred</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_14">
		<text>Bid: 3 thousand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_15">
		<text>Bid: 35 hundred</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_16">
		<text>Bid: 4 thousand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_17">
		<text>Bid: 5 thousand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_18">
		<text>Refused.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_19">
		<text>All right - Bid is done, now wait for the message. Good luck dude!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_20">
		<text>Okay, I'll go...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_21">
		<text>You Labelled with oak fell chtoli? You've got more than a hundred pieces, and you are prohibited from making bids. Come on tomatoes moving away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="totalizator_22">
		<text>The evil you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="give_prize_0">
		<text>Suslov's great - I for donations and.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="give_prize_1">
		<text>Right now let's see what's owed to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="give_prize_2">
		<text>Come on - do not pull the rubber. Get the loot.</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="give_prize_3">
		<text>Weather ... Right now ... Open safe.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="give_prize_4">
		<text>Withdraw money.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="give_prize_5">
		<text>Leave on for storage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="give_dolg_0">
		<text>Suslov - this is payback came to give.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="give_dolg_1">
		<text>Okay - debt for you no more. Single.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="take_deposit_0">
		<text>Pick up the deposit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="take_deposit_1">
		<text>Choose how you want to remove.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="take_deposit_2">
		<text>Remove 10% of the.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="take_deposit_3">
		<text>Remove half of the amount.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="take_deposit_4">
		<text>Remove the entire amount.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="take_deposit_5">
		<text>Well, hold.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="take_deposit_6">
		<text>Thank you for that well-kept Suslov. I will go relax Maleh.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="news_1">
		<text>Yes, Spot is not your day today. Bid Your not play - MNT zero gain.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_2">
		<text>Win 50 rubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_3">
		<text>Win 1 hundred RUB.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_4">
		<text>Win 5 hundred RUB.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_5">
		<text>Win 1 thousand RUB.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_6">
		<text>Win 15 hundred RUB.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_7">
		<text>Win 2 thousand RUB.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_8">
		<text>Win 25 hundred RUB.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_9">
		<text>Win 5 thousand RUB.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_10">
		<text>Win 10 thousand RUB.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="news_11">
		<text>Win 20 thousand RUB.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_12">
		<text>Win 30 thousand RUB.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_13">
		<text>Win 40 thousand RUB.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_14">
		<text>Win 50 thousand RUB.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="news_15">
		<text>Jack Pot Spot! You Win 100 thousand RUB.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="dolg_1">
		<text>Labeled here you asked about dolzhka...\nYou would have looked, and gave - a penny remained the same.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_2">
		<text>Aya-ay I'm tagging, then the term has passed, and you do not bring a payback in a hurry. Let's hurry up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_3">
		<text>And what does it mean Spot? You have given time?\nDali. The term came out - Dui here with money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_4">
		<text>So, so tagging, so we love to play, but give no debts.\nIt is not good. Even vice-versa - it is bad. Hands for this tear is necessary. Understood?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_5">
		<text>Labelled you even brazen. What the hell are you I ask you carry no debt?\nThen the guys came and promised to cut you to the British flag, and what's left - the flesh to feed. Come see me alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_6">
		<text>I do not understand human. We like dogovarilivalis?\nDuty for three days - and no, "but I could not, I'm sorry".\nDo what you want, but the debt is returned immediately. Otherwise - you kranty.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="dolg_7">
		<text>Come quickly labeled on the base "Pure Heaven" by Suslov.\nYou expect ... On the bubble. Otherwise, blame yourself - ax is sharpened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_8">
		<text>Well, you and Spot pig - you're a bitch I expose that money do not give.\nIf the evening did not bring back the debt - the entrance to the base you will be closed forever.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_9">
		<text>Last warning Chinese Spot:\nall the time went, and you even lifted a finger!\nYes, you will enscribe, if you loot will not come back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dolg_10">
		<text>Tagged - you're dead.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- added 109919 -->
	<string id="net_pda">
		<text>netpacket PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="desc_net_pda">
		<text>Please keep your hands off this Device!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bolt_pda">
		<text>Bolt PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="desc_bolt_pda">
		<text>Bolt PDA. Content requires careful study</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sci_flash">
		<text>Scientist Flash card</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>
