<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.0 The Doctor, something, Crest -->

	<string id="escape_meceniy_start_0">
		<text>Greetings, who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_meceniy_start_1">
		<text>Greetings, Im a former Military man, here now I do a little trading. But my goods are specific, I sell rare nodes for activation of anomalies. Also I sell PSI antidote and serum, very rare in the zone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_meceniy_start_2">
		<text>Well, I see many military men turn into dealers. It is not an easy life in the Ukrainian military. What's your name? Iam known as the Marked One.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_meceniy_start_3">
		<text>My name is Akim, pleasant to get acquainted. Yes in the military it's a rough life, and the retirement pension is worse. Now I trade, resell, and buy. In general I don't bargain so don't bother. I've come to the zone to make my fortune and then get out of this hell hole. And into the account of nodes, stalkers sometimes sell artefacts in the form of a Shell, they can activate anomalies. Glance in the PDA, there should be information. By the way I have a colleage in the Agroprom northern complex who sells wares similar to what I offer. He has a lot of helpful information. If your looking for work there's a colleage I know who has settled down by the helicopter in the Forgotten wood.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="arhara_halat_nayti_0">
		<text>Listen, I heard about a strange jacket. While wearing it you can sneak up and steal up close to the enemy, have you heard about such a jacket?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_halat_nayti_1">
		<text>Yes, I know of it. Only it's not a jacket, it's an Exoskeleton. I know that it was missing after the last scientific expedition to the Zone center. It is not difficult to guess that it is now in the possesion of bandits. My intelligence officer has told me it's in the ATP. I sent a sqaud there to retrieve it, but for a long time there's been no contact so I assume the worst. I can't spare anymore men at the moment but I know only approximately where it's located, in an attic of one of the buildings. If you could find this exoskeleton? I will be very grateful!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_halat_nayti_2">
		<text>I can't guarantee anything, but if I am in that territory I will have a look. But if I find it, I might need to use it myself for awhile.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_halat_nayti_3">
		<text>Well I don't like the sound of this. Find someone else, my skin is more expensive than an Exoskeleton.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="arhara_halat_otdat_0">
		<text>Greetings chief. I have found that Exoskeleton. A first class piece!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_halat_otdat_1">
		<text>Yes!! You have brought it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_halat_otdat_2">
		<text>Here you are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_halat_otdat_3">
		<text>Well done! Take the reward.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="escape_adrenalin_start_0">
		<text>Greetings, who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_adrenalin_start_1">
		<text>Greetings, I am the local dealer. I specialize in unique wares. Such as Nodes which you can turn into anomalies. I also sell serum and the rare antidote to PSI sickness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_adrenalin_start_2">
		<text>Yes, there was a conversation with Akim about you. Jack up the price alot, do you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_adrenalin_start_3">
		<text>This means Akim has not yet forgotten about his workmate! And the price is decent, but also you will find my goods are specific and rare.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="atp_0">
		<text>Greetings Adrenalin, I'm trying to find better weapons for my campaign to the center of the zone. Can you help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_1">
		<text>Greetings, I can't offer much in weaponry, but a good sniper rifle I can offer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_2">
		<text>Sounds really expensive, money and artefacts are in short supply at the moment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_3">
		<text>For this sniper rifle, money's not good enogh! But there is a way you can earn it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_4">
		<text>How do I do that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_5">
		<text>I need you to visit the scientist in Yantar. Sakharov is his surname. Talk to him about the Military commander who somtimes comes for business. I have an order for a Minigun I need you to pick up. Easy job, you want it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_6">
		<text>I could use a good sniper rifle and this doesn't sound too dangerous. Yes, I'll go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="atp_7">
		<text>Drag a heavy Minigun across the Zone, no thanks!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="arhara_atp_propusk_0">
		<text>Hello, Adrenalin!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_atp_propusk_1">
		<text>Did you bring the weapon?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_atp_propusk_2">
		<text>Here you are, glad to get that wieght off my back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arhara_atp_propusk_3">
		<text>Excellent Marked One! Here take this sniper rifle, and in addition this artefact.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="trader_toha_0">
		<text>Im looking for some work, do you have any jobs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_toha_1">
		<text>Work??? Ive got a lot of work, you came to the right place stalker. First lets see if you have the stomach for the job. Bring to me 10 zombie hands. you up for that??</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_toha_2">
		<text>Wow, zombie hands! I didn't expect you to ask for something like that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_toha_3">
		<text>It's a strange strange world stalker, and by the look of your clothes I would say your in a financial crisis.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_toha_4">
		<text>It certainly is a strange world, even stranger when you can't remember who you are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_toha_5">
		<text>Well stalker, do I have a new employee? If I can offer a bit of advice about zombie hunting, you gotta shoot em in the head!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_toha_6">
		<text>Shoot em in the head? something tells me Ive heard that before! Yea, Ill take the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_toha_7">
		<text>Get ten zombie hands!!! No Way!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="trader_toha1_0">
		<text>Here's your zombie hands, strange how the finger nails grew an inch while they were in my backpack.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_toha1_1">
		<text>I'm going to have to give them a pedicure before I can ship them out! Ha, Ha. Thanks, Here as promised your reward. Yes scissors grind, Doh! Oh, look how crookedly I have cut the nails!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_toha1_2">
		<text>While your doing your nails, I'm gonna wash out this backpack.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="trader_toha1_3">
		<text>You really need to buy a new knife, it looks like you chewed through these wrists!</text>
	</string>


	<string id="doc_qeast_0">
		<text>What's next Dr. Frankenstein? I'm ready to do another job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_1">
		<text>Did you get some new armor?, or maybe you just had a wash. Your starting to resemble a modern stalker! There is one order of business tho, I've learned that there are documents which will enable me to create something important.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_2">
		<text>Sounds better already, no body parts! What do I need to do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_3">
		<text>No body parts this time, just documents.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_4">
		<text>Where do I search for these documents?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_5">
		<text>The documents are located on a roof in the Garbage. Could be a building, a bus, or a shipping container. It's impossible to read the other part of the note.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_6">
		<text>On a roof? It would be all the same to simply say, in the Garbage. Ok at least it's not zombie hands!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_7">
		<text>What do you think I am, a police dog? Find your own piece of paper.</text>
	</string>


	<string id="doc_qeast01_0">
		<text>I risked my ass for this piece of paper? Here's your documents and don't forget my reward!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast01_1">
		<text>And what ass did you risk? Did you shit your pants? I said that on a roof, not in a manure heap!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast01_2">
		<text>Risk! What do you know about risk?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast01_3">
		<text>Calm down, it's a joke! Take the reward.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="doc_qeast_p_0">
		<text>Greetings, I have come for more work. I gather resources for a distant campaign, and the barman doesn't give anything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_p_1">
		<text>I too don't give out credit to you. However, your help to me is required. Those documents that you brought are only the first part of the full document. There is also a second part.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_p_2">
		<text>Again you send me to find old paper.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_p_3">
		<text>You catch on quick. Improbably, I see the eyes of a monkey turn to that of a person!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_p_4">
		<text>Listen, as a descendant of Darwin I will transform you into a monkey, only a knife I will use! Now, where do I search for the second part of the documents?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_p_5">
		<text>Has your humour gone flat? Search in the Agropom underground.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_p_6">
		<text>I will try to find them. But this task, I think, will be more expensive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_p_7">
		<text>Akim, you after all were a fighter, go yourself to the Agropom underground.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="doc_qeast_p1_0">
		<text>Here's your documents, you could be a bit more exact with your information. I after all am not telepathic nor am I Sherlock Holmes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_p1_1">
		<text>Yes, I see that crinkled documents are your specialty. Please fold them neatly and put them in your backpack instead of stuffing them into your pockets! It's a joke good fellow, thanks, here's your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_p1_2">
		<text>Thanks, and I've got plenty of brains. Even some to spare, looks like you could use some!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_p1_3">
		<text>Your easy to wind up, stalker.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="doc_qeast_s_0">
		<text>Hello Akim. How is the life of trade? I don't see stalkers lineing up to buy your goods.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_s_1">
		<text>Greetings, Marked One. It's about the qaulity of the sales not the qauntity. Once again I need to employ your talents. Wind in X-18. I can't find anybody willing to go there. And to risk my own expensive head is out of the question.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_s_2">
		<text>Akim what are you babbleing about? Wind in X-18?!!! The sun deck open up there? let's all go there to have a rest and live the high life! I will go, but you will pay well for this 'Sun Deck' adventure!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_s_3">
		<text>The blessing of money, Marked One. These documents could put me on the fast-track to that beach paradise that awaits me when I leave the zone!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_s_4">
                <text>Now I understand your rambleings. Let's get down to business, gimme some details.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_s_5">
		<text>Well, studying the second part of the documents has led me to the third part. I have found out that somebody called Korchagin had this document, and divided it into four parts. In laboratory X-18 are three parts of the document. Somewhere outside the lab within the compound is the fourth part. Find them all for me. My gratitude will not know borders!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_s_6">
		<text>Let's test the 'borders' of your gratitude.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_s_7">
		<text>Ive had enough of underground labs, go yourself!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="doc_qeast_s1_0">
		<text>I've returned with the documents, not an easy task but some interesting loot was found.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_s1_1">
		<text>This excellent. Now I have enough information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_s1_2">
		<text>Akim, stop drooling on the documents. Give my reward!!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_s1_3">
		<text>It is fine, fine. Here, take this, you earned it!</text>
	</string>



	<string id="doc_qeast_q_0">
		<text>Greetings, I see you have now mastered the alphabet by reading all the secret documents.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_q_1">
		<text>Greetings, after X-18 your crinkles have absolutely ceased! But, your services are necessary again. I need you to descend into lab X-16 and find one more document. Also I need you to bring a PDA from Borov's base in the Dark Valley.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_q_2">
		<text>Akim, explain, why all these documents. Your like a gambler chasing a winning hand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_q_3">
		<text>The details of my motivations are not for your concern.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_q_4">
		<text>My mind can wander sometimes, but I'm smarter than you think. So tell me the details of this task.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_q_5">
		<text>I was mistaken, I thought that after lab X-18 you were not on friendly terms with your own mind. But now I can see it's a condition you've had since childhood. On to the business at hand, one part of the key that you have brought back from lab X-18 appeares not to be last part of this puzzle. But it has shed light onto a new document and PDA in which there is essential data. Find them, I know the approximate location of the PDA. Search around the crane in front of Borov's base. The document should be in the control room of lab X-16. And still there is more that is needed, one each of the following armors:\n Military CKAT-10, the Exoskeleton of Stalkers, the Exoskeleton of Bandits, the Scientific Suit of Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_q_6">
		<text>I see, at my expense you try to update the assortment of your shop! I accept, this might take some time to gather all this gear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_q_7">
		<text>You ask too much this time, Im leaving.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="doc_qeast_q1_0">
		<text>Where should I unload the truck? Are you sure you don't want to add Cinderella's shoe to the list? Here's all your gear!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_q1_1">
		<text>I didn't expect you to find it all! Time to listen to what I have learned, these instructions I have will suffice to collect a model of a new Exoskeleton. In the Zone there is one trial copy. I give to you the detailed instructions, look don't lose the confidential data. If you lose it you will not be able to understand! Good luck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_q1_2">
		<text>This is great! I appreciate the instructions, this looks very useful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_qeast_q1_3">
		<text>When you find it, inform me on how it works.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="doc_tvar_0">
		<text>Greetings trading Guru! Long live the fair deceit of stalkers!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_tvar_1">
		<text>I think you had many problems as a child. Business is, parts of mutants, one of each, except zombie hands. This is not a difficult task for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_tvar_2">
		<text>Why do you want such a collection? Planning a buffet night?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_tvar_3">
		<text>By the way, after you leave the Zone I suggest you apply for work at the Post Office. Without a gun in your hands, licking stamps is the only skill I think you posess! I will await the spare parts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_tvar_4">
		<text>The only stamps I would paste would be on your forehead. By the way, that's not a bad idea!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_tvar_5">
		<text>Listen, it's about time you visited the The Doctor. Let him give you a good enema to clean out your brains that are clogging up your arse. You going to collect parts of mutants or not?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_tvar_6">
		<text>I'll give you an enema with a flamethrower! I'm away to gather mutant parts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_tvar_7">
		<text>No Akim, it's time for you to do your own work.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="doc_tvar1_0">
		<text>Greetings, Collector. I have brought the full set. Prepare your knife and fork.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_tvar1_1">
		<text>I asked you to bring spare parts. What sloppy butchery, you bring whole arms instead of hands and what's with the whole cat!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_tvar1_2">
		<text>Here's a hand, there's a foot, there's a tail. Whats' not there? You can make jelly from what remains!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doc_tvar1_3">
		<text>Oh God, allow me to remain silent! Here, take the reward.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="qeast_q_0">
		<text>What the hell are you doing way out here, come to collect mushrooms?, haha.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="qeast_q_1">
		<text>Greetings Stalker, I am Crest. And just for the record mushrooms don't grow here. I've come to this place for artefacts. There are lots of them, unfortunately not the ones I'm looking for. Will you help me collect? I need fifteen artefacts,  five pieces of each kind: Medusa, Stone Flower, and Fireball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="qeast_q_2">
		<text>Fifteen artefacts? That's a big task for any stalker. Tell me why I just shouldn't walk away and just forget I ever met you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="qeast_q_3">
		<text>Yes it's a big job!, but I promise the reward will be fair!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="qeast_q_4">
		<text>I don't know, that's a lot of radiation to be carrying around in my backpack and besides Im a busy man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="qeast_q_5">
		<text>Well Stalker look around. You can see I come equiped, I'm someone you can trust and that's an uncommon thing in the Zone. Make the right friends and you never know how useful they might become in the future.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="qeast_q_6">
		<text>Yes there's so much deceit and betrayal in the Zone and I hope you speak truthfully! Well, I will bring the fifteen artefacts and I will expect payment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="qeast_q_7">
		<text>Crest, collect them yourself, that's too much radiation to be carrying around.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="qeast_q1_0">
		<text>Greetings Crest. Here take your artefacts, all this radiation is unhealthy. I don't want to become impotent!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="qeast_q1_1">
		<text>Great job, Marked One!, thanks. Judging by the fourteen artefacts on your belt, you've already had too much radiation exposure! Well, in general, with health you do not radiate, you might already be impotent. Here's your award.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="qeast_q1_2">
		<text>What the hell do you know about impotence!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="qeast_q1_3">
		<text>Calm down, don't get angry. It's something to think about, if you stay in the Zone too long you'll end up a drooling like a Zombie.. picking your nose all day.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="m_qeast_0">
		<text>Greetings.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="m_qeast_1">
		<text>Once again the hero of the Zone has visited me. There is a job for you! Yesterday the military raided me and took all my artefacts! Well, all that I didn't have stashed! And they also drank all my vodka! It is necessary to punish them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="m_qeast_2">
		<text>Punish Military men?!, yea, your right!, they did drink all the vodka, bastards! Have you thought about the consequences though? I after all am not a killer for hire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="m_qeast_3">
		<text>I'm not asking you to kill anybody! Can you get me thier abnormal weaponry? I need six Bisons, then I can hire and arm some men to give them something to think about next time they raid.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="m_qeast_4">
		<text>Oh, you mean I approach them say: Hey, Soldiers!, give me six Bisons! And they, with pleasure, will give them to me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="m_qeast_5">
		<text>My money, 40,000ru, and an aditional reward is the offer. How you get the guns is up to you. If you will agree I will eagerly wait for them like a teenage boy craves for young girls.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="m_qeast_6">
		<text>OK I will do it, That's a lot of money and so far I've picked up a couple of Bison on my travels and most likley will find more!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="m_qeast_7">
		<text>No, I'm not looking for trouble with the military. These people will send a pair of helicopters to blast me to pieces, then pseudodogs will feast on my brains!</text>
	</string>

	<string id="m_qeast1_0">
		<text>Here, I have brought the Bisons. But no young girls for you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="m_qeast1_1">
		<text>Fantastic Marked One! Here's your award.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="m_qeast1_2">
		<text>These are deadly weapons, I should know I've been in thier sights more times than I care to remember!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="m_qeast1_3">
		<text>I Hope that it wasn't too difficult? Though that's a doubtful question.</text>
	</string>



	<string id="s_qeast_0">
		<text>Are you the local Tarzan, or are you here to trade with Chimeras?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="s_qeast_1">
		<text>You make jokes Marked One, good to see the Zone hasn't taken your sense of humor. And for you there is still a task. Ah! How your eyes light up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="s_qeast_2">
		<text>The thought of earning elite artefacts make them shine brightly! What's the task?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="s_qeast_3">
		<text>There is a military man who went missing in these woods. He has in his possession a teleporter that I would like to examine. From monitoring his communications I know he had to stay the night in these woods because the teleporter is defective. He described his position as being next to some big stones and a recently abandoned car. Yesterday I met a Stalker who said his car broke down in the northern part of the woods, so it's not far from here. Find the soldier and bring me the teleporter and I will reward you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="s_qeast_4">
		<text>Something stinks! What kind of mess are you sending me into?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="s_qeast_5">
		<text>This teleporter is important to me, it is a necessary risk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="s_qeast_6">
		<text>Necessary for ME to take all the risk is more like it, I will look for this soildier and his gadget.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="s_qeast_7">
		<text>Crest, you milk wild boars! Don't piss me off, understand.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="s_qeast1_0">
		<text>I've found the teleporter, only it doesn't work. Here take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="s_qeast1_1">
		<text>I knew you would try to use it. I told you it didn't work. I will repair it. And what of the military man?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="s_qeast1_2">
		<text>Mutants must have killed him recently.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="s_qeast1_3">
		<text>Thanks Marked One, here is your reward. And by the way, under the device cover there is a stamp with an inscription 'Prototype 2'. Meaning the first copy is still somwhere in the Zone. If you find it, it's yours. Judging by the markings, both devices were made in the ATP, that's where I'd start. There's also more concrete evidence, by monitoring radio traffic of local bandits' they are expecting to be raided by the military and have hidden some of thier loot. So it would be wise to look in the Garbage containers in the ATP, for certain you'll find something there.</text>
	</string>