<!-- TB3D 1.0.9.9.9.8 Sealside and TB edits June 18, 2012, removed "string_table" - aleks1970 -->

	<string id="rad_chief_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Hello!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_chief_start_dialog_100">
		<text>Greetings!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_deputy_dialog_1_0">
		<text>Where's the money for the task?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_deputy_dialog_1_100">
		<text>Find my assistant, and there will be for you money!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_deputy_dialog_1_1000">
		<text>It is good, but this time without deceit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_1_0">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_1_10">
		<text>Leha the Jaw they call me! And these tramps - my brigade!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_1_100">
		<text>What are you and your people doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_1_20">
	<!-- Sealside word changes  -->
		<text>Me and my children will take a rest here! Afterwards, we will go to Pripyat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_2_0">
		<text>What do you know about Pripyat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_2_10">
	<!-- Sealside rewrite -->
		<text>I know that it is an old abandoned city from the epoch of communism!\nNow it is just crowded with monsters and Monolithians. Those who have gone before me did not return, none.\n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_2_100">
	<!-- Sealside rewrite  -->
		<text>Don't you think it is very dangerous to go there, then?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_2_20">
	<!-- Sealside  rewrite-->
		<text>No doubts about that, you are right. But I am sure it is worth trying.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_0">
	<!-- Sealside minor -->
		<text>Did you see military nearby?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_10">
	<!-- Sealside rewrite -->
		<text>No, fortunatelly not. It has been quite a while since they showed up the last time here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_100">
	<!-- Sealside  rewrite-->
		<text>Not even military Stalkers?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_20">
	<!-- Sealside major rewrite -->
		<text>I heard some of them appeared in the radar region, near the antennas! As they were disconnected, many people started traveling to the Radar and further to Pripyat! But we did not meet any further people coming from the wharehouses since we came here. Likely, someone has blocked the road here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_200">
	<!-- Sealside rewrite... i pretty much rewrite everything here, i won't set a rewrite note in from anymore; expect everything to be written entirly new. -->
		<text>Blocked, you say? By whom, what do you think? The military?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_30">
		<text>As I said, the military didn't show up for a long time; hence, it could've been the military stalkers. Those are tough bastards, and they operate really quickly and harmoniously. I wonder they did not block the road earlier!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_300">
		<text>Wouldn't it be more clever to go Pripyat and block the entrance there?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_3_40">
		<text>I do not know, maybe they fear proceeding, or they are preparing for something. It is useless to guess what's on their mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_0">
		<text>Well, anyway... do you have a task for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_10">
		<text>Well, there is one, but it is not easy... Still interested, Stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_100">
		<text>Yes, I'm not afraid of hard work!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_101">
		<text>Not easy, hmm... Well, no, you'll have to find someone else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_11">
		<text>I understand... I am afraid myself, I prefer to spend money and send someone instead of myself or my people. What a pity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_20">
	<!-- Sealside  major rewrite all the way down...-->
		<text>Well, alright!\nSo, here is your task: My scouts, Loma and Log, have been sent to Pripyat to check how bad the situation really is, but they did not return yet.\n Try to find them alive and bring them back safely... If this is not possible, at least bring their guns back, they were good ones, and we need them here!\nI will give you 2000 if you complete this task for me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_200">
		<text>Seems fair to me, I'll bring your men back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_201">
		<text>2000? You got to be kidding me. This task must be worth 4000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_21">
		<text>I'm sorry, Stalker. 2000 is all I can offer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_find_stalkers_dialog_4_30">
		<text>Excellent, I'll wait here for you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_0">
		<text>Marked One reporting... Task is executed!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_100">
		<text>Perfect! Give me his PDA!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1000">
		<text>Hold on, mate. First show the money!</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Sealside note: the original text did not make any sense. tried to make the best of it, tough it could be wrong in the context -->
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1100">
		<text>Stupid scum. I guess he has nothing!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1200">
		<text>Please, stop kidding me. You don't want to challenge me, do you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1300">
		<text>I'd rather just kill you off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_1400">
		<text>Alright I understand. Good luck, then...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_200">
		<text>I can give nothing to you, money is not present. If you want, you can have his stuff!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_1_300">
		<text>Nevermind... It's for free, then. I'm not interested in his stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_2_0">
		<text>I did not found it yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_deputy_dialog_2_10">
		<text>Well, better hurry up if you want to get your money, Stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_0">
		<text>I have found your men, but they were dead already. I can't tell what killed them, I had to draw them out of a chimera's claws. Their weapons seem to be intact, here they are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_100">
		<text>Oh, shit. Those were my best men... Now where they are all gone, I think there is no sense in going to Pripyat... I don't want to lead my men into a suicide mission! One problem remains, I cannot give you money for the task. My assistant ran away with it all the money... Please understand, Marked One.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_1001">
		<text>I will find him! Tell me where to search. And don't try to cheat on me. You'd be a dead man in, like, 5 seconds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_200">
		<text>I think he did not get far I will note it on the map, here or here! If you find him, return him here. If he "accidently" died, his PDA would be enough... Got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_1_2000">
		<text>Well, wait for me! I will bring your PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_2_0">
		<text>I have not found them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rad_found_stalkers_dialog_2_10">
		<text>Find them faster! I cannot wait here eternally!!! Good luck!</text>
	</string>
