<!-- TB3D 1.0.9.9.9.8 dialog improvements -->
	<string id="about_enciclopedia">
		<text>This is the Encyclopedia. As you progress in the game, information about the world around you will be added here. Sorted by topic.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="about_pda">
		<text>About the Encyclopedia</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bandit's flash">
		<text>Factory Bandit's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="blokpost_case_text">
		<text>Trader: get inside the Army Outpost and steal the case containing the report on the Military's expedition into the northern part of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Dead novice's flash">
		<text>Dead Rookie's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="defend_lager_text">
		<text>Fanatic: Help us defend against the Mercs who ordered the Rookies to clear out of the camp. The plan goes like that. Everyone hides, so the camp looks deserted, we let the Mercs inside the camp, then attack on the Captain's orders ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doctor_meet">
		<text>Guide's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doctor_meet_2">
		<text>Meeting the Doctor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doctor_meet_quest_text">
		<text>Doctor: I will be waiting for a man who comes from Strelok to the hiding place used by Strelok and his men. If he's our man, he'll know the place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="doctor_meet_text">
		<text>OK, I'll meet with Ghost's man. I will be waiting for him in Strelok's hiding place. If he's one of our own, he will know where to look for me. Doctor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_flash_task_descr">
		<text>Some people working for Sidorovich were coming back from an assignment up north, when the patrol dissapeared somewhere near the Cordon. One of them, a Stalker called Nimble, was carrying a Flash-drive with important information. This Flash-drive is real important for Sidorovich so we have to find the Flash-drive and get it back to him. Sidorovich thinks Wolf, the veteran Stalker in the Rookie Camp, might know more of the whereabouts of the missing patrol. I need to talk to Wolf, and see if he knows anything, he presumably can give me a weapon and some gear..
</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fox_info">
		<text>Serly to Fox: a friend wants me to give a helping hand to a bunch of STALKERs that dug out Strelok's stash. I'm off to the hangar at the Garbage with my boys. That's where you can find me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kolyan_lost">
		<text>Yesterday one Brother went to Scout the deserted mill and we haven't heard from him since. We need to go there and see where he disappeared to ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="factory_dynamit_text">
		<text>Wolf: bring the dynamite stolen by the Bandits at the factory. To help you, there are Scouts under the bridge, come to them and say "Hello from the Underworld" - that's the password. Lead them into battle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="factory_trader_text">
		<text>Wolf: clear the Bandits at the factory with the help of my Scouts behind the bridge, then return and report to me ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Flash dead stalker">
		<text>Dead stalker's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="gunslinger_clan_cache">
		<text>...Can't remember anything ... all I have is this PDA on me with a picture of someone I don't know, and have never seen before. It's hard to tell. His face is covered. I just don't know. There's just one message in the PDA - "Kill Strelok"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="help_to_fox">
		<text>Sidorovich has sent us a message. Apparently a Stalker named Fox has come back from a raid up north, and is in serious troubles. Sid didn't exactly know what Fox's problem was, but it hat to do with some vicous type of mutants chasing him. Go to the burned down House on the road north of the bridge, and help Fox. Maybe he also knows something about the this 'Strelok' person.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="meet_seryi_text">
		<text>Fox want's us to meet up with his brother, Seriy, who is residing in the hanger in the Garbage area. Seriy knows more about Strelok, so Fox thinks it's wise to have a chat with him while he is still there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="military_case_text">
		<text>Sidorovich want's us to travel north towards the Garbage, and follow the road west towards the Agroprom Research Institute. There is an Military encampment in these regions, and rumours have it that there are some very important documents inside the base at this moment. Travel towards the Agroprom vicinity as fast as possible, find a way inside the Military headquarters and steal the documents. As soon as you have the case with the documents, take it to the Bartender. He runs the 100RADS Bar in the former Rostok area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Seryi flash">
		<text>Fox's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="storyline_fox_flash_info">
		<text>Tolik's Diary: Trader sent us to spy on the Military at the Agroprom Research Institute. Got there and shot everybody, Bandits and Military alike. Dug out some interesting stuff, I'm encoding the rest ... *gibberish text that looks like a cipher*</text>
	</string>
	<string id="storyline_seryi_info">
		<text>Serly to Fox: One guy I know asked to meet a group of STALKERs who sniffed out Strelok's hiding place. I'll be at the Garbage, come over if you want ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Tolik flash">
		<text>Tolik's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_artefact_find">
		<text>Trader: there is a Whirligig Anomaly field close by. There is an artefact in its center. Get it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_moving_anomaly_text">
		<text>There's a very strange anomaly here. It looks like it's moving. I'll try to calculate its movement times and path, because I don't have the cash to pay the soldiers for passage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_secret_place">
		<text>I left a small cache at the deserted farm. It's got some food and ammo. I'm way too weak to carry it now. I'm not sure if I can make it to the camp.</text>
	</string>
