<!-- TB3D 1.0.9.9.9.8 minor edits, kostya hints, tex_saharov_pda -->
	<string id="mil_actor_main_quest_descr">
		<text>According to General Voronin, this gun is only at grouping "Freedom" as I will get it - my business. But as I have understood, one of ways is to be rubbed in trust to the stalker of "Freedom" to the Cook. According to the general, he's a big fan of drink. So it is necessary just in case bring vodka, it can be useful for getting information from loose lips eh...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_blockpost_job_descr">
		<text>It is necessary to help to protect the Barrier from attack from party from "Brain Scorcher".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_blockpost_job2_descr">
		<text>Lukash: "If you feel in yourself forces you can go to the outpost at the exit to the Radar. To some signs the next attempt of break of mutants or "the Monolith" there is expected. It is necessary to help children".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_courier_doc_descr">
		<text>"Freedom" had grenade cup discharges of type RG-6. Two pieces. One in an arsenal, the second somewhere in the village.\n\n</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_courier_job_descr">
		<text>Lukash: "Regrettably to recognise, however at us the informer was got... Pavlik call. The information transfers to the party, and this business should be stopped. Your problem - to follow him to the farm and to learn, to whom he hands over the information. He has left recently, so it is necessary to catch up. Remember: kill him when it is possible and it is necessary, but not earlier, then it will come to light to whom he gives the information. The second party should be killed too".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_crazy_flash_info">
		<text>... Today we have gone to the village on the next hunting. All as always.\n\n... This creature whence undertook? Not otherwise, as from the Radar has climbed through. All dead, I'm alone... I will try to leave at night...\n\n... I do not remember, how I have got out is there was a present hell... My head hurts - images, sounds, I do not know whence they undertake, devil's radiation. And the gauge, a bough, has broken. I should have a rest, and to me it becomes easier.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_dolg_kill_lukash_descr">
		<text>Come with Dutiers to the base\nDestroy three snipers\nKill Lukash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_dolg_kill_sniper_descr">
		<text>Kill the sniper on a tower. It is necessary to operate accurately not to obtain a bullet in the head.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_flash_bandit_descr">
		<text>Pancake, goats from "Duty" have driven us from a base. Were dug round on our farm. We didn't even have time to get our stuff. Anything, base of "Freedom" nearby so them quickly therefrom will smoke.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_flash_max_descr">
		<text>Today military men who went to the Radar, had a pair of RG-6. A class piece. One took Lukash, and the second Gloomy has hidden in the village, in a house cellar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_flash_ugrumy_descr">
		<text>1. Lines me has pulled to go on the Radar, has hardly slipped - a little more, and there would be one more exhibit with dissolved brains.\n\n2. Four bandits have surrounded me as small, and I am good - have missed an ambush. I was rescued by their garrulity and greed, instead of that that me to honeycomb, they have jumped out and have wanted me to undress preliminary - have coveted a suit. It was their last error, but one all the same me a reserve. Oh, I grow old...\n\n3. The envoy Strelok to my arrival did not breathe any more. Yes, with three bloodsuckers not everyone will consult, and this has laid a four, and some more trails of blood leave every which way. The unique information which was at it, is a code of a door (19840519) but from what, possibility to learn yet is not represented.\n\n4. Have intercepted fighters who went to the Radar. Documents and orders at them was not, but at least, ammunition. I will put the RG-6 in this cellar, then I will take away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_freedom_rg6_task_descr">
		<text>Voronin: Freedom "has some excellent grenade discharges RG-6 if at you it has turned out to get on territory of "Freedom" and steal at least one such grenade discharger I generously would remunerate you. As you not in our grouping, you can easily be rubbed in trust to "Freedom" and at a successful deal to filch RG-6. I will send to you the information on the base site of "Freedom". There you should find a certain Cook, a member of "Freedom", he knows, where exactly is stored RG-6. He is weak on binge, therefore try it. Take for this purpose more vodka".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_go_to_miser_descr">
		<text>Hm. The award will be given out by the Miser on the base of "Freedom"... The Good name. Can though on delayed conserve will show a bit of generosity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_hunters_task_descr">
		<text>Destroy bloodsuckers in village. They can operate accurately, and can leave me without blood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_hunters_task_descr2">
		<text>Destroy bloodsuckers in village. They can operate accurately, and can leave me without blood.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_lukash_job_descr">
		<text>Lukash has decided to put counterstrike on Group "Duty" on farm. Operation will be headed by Max - one of the veterans of "Freedom". My task - to help them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_mad_flash_job_descr">
		<text>That, interesting, this madman on a swamp can know such? We will understand. The main thing not to run into old mines, but they should be in so rusty a condition that they will blow up from a bolt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_kostya_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in Cordon. It is necessary to search in the wood near to the abandoned factory.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="esc_kostya_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in Cordon. At the cross south of tracks under a fir-tree.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="esc_kostya_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in Cordon. To the east of the rookie village under stones.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_kordon_art">
		<text>Bring Kostya an artefact "goldfish" from the abandoned factory in Cordon.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_svalka_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in Garbage. Look behind wood under dangling legs behind a bog.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_svalka_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in Garbage. Look in west woods behind parking that is behind the machinery graveyard.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_svalka_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in Garbage. Look in a crain box on a radioactive heap which is closest to the cemetery of vehicles.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_svalka_taynik4">
		<text>Hiding place in Garbage. Look on a radioactive heap which is the closest to a wood behind the swamp. Is not on the ground.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_svalka_taynik5">
		<text>Hiding place in Garbage. Look on a radioactive heap which is located near to the Duty post.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_x18_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in laboratory X-18. Look in the laboratory, according to all available information it should be somewhere there. It is said that it is hidden indoors with an old safe.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_x18_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in laboratory X-18. Look in the laboratory, according to all available information it should be somewhere there. It is said that it is hidden indoors with old cages.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_x18_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in laboratory X-18. Look in the laboratory, according to all available information it should be somewhere there. It is said that it is hidden indoors where the pseudo-giant lives. It is necessary to look above.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_agroprom_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in Agroprom. It is necessary to search in a bog.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_agroprom_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in Agroprom. Look to the south from the complex where fighters have sat down at radiation center.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_agroprom_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in Agroprom. It is hidden near to support LEP.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_agroprom_taynik4">
		<text>Hiding place in Agroprom. To the north from the central complex at a den of tushkanos in a bush.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_agroprom_taynik5">
		<text>Hiding place in Agroprom. Around dwelling of cats in a bush.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_agroprom_taynik6">
		<text>Hiding place in Agroprom. In a ravine between complexes.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_yantar_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in Yantar. "Prosir-butane" in factory territory is hidden under a butt.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_yantar_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in Yantar. It is hidden in factory territory in the container from under garbage.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_yantar_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in Yantar. It is hidden in factory territory in a pipe.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_yantar_taynik4">
		<text>Hiding place in Yantar. It is hidden in factory territory on a tree.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_yantar_taynik5">
		<text>Hiding place in Yantar. It is hidden in factory territory on one of capacities.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_yantar_taynik6">
		<text>Hiding place in Yantar. It is hidden in factory territory on a high pipe.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_as_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in Army Warehouses. Look around the helicopter, under one of the fir-trees.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_as_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in Army Warehouses. Look in village of bloodsuckers in one of the houses in an oven.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_as_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in Army Warehouses. Look in village of bloodsuckers in a chimney.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_as_taynik4">
		<text>Hiding place in Army Warehouses. Look in village of bloodsuckers on a tree.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_as_taynik5">
		<text>Hiding place in Army Warehouses. Look in village of bloodsuckers on a roof ridge.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_as_taynik6">
		<text>Hiding place in Army Warehouses. Look in the minefield.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_radar_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in the Radar. Do not pass by the helicopter. Should be somewhere there.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_radar_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in the Radar. In wood on a tree near to the hole in the mesh protection.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_radar_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in the Radar. In wood on stones near to a carriage.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_radar_taynik4">
		<text>Hiding place in the Radar. In wood on a tree. It is necessary to go from a carriage along rocks, and you will see.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_x10_taynik">
		<text>Hiding place in laboratory X-10. To open a door in X-10, it is necessary to learn the code. The help on code drawing up is in a hiding place in this laboratory. Under the help it will be necessary to make a code of available numbers. Numbers 9, 7, 2, 54, 61.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_pripyat_taynik1">
		<text>Hiding place in Pripyat. There should be three hiding places in Pripyat. One - in a kindergarten. The second - in hotel. The third - in one of apartment houses.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_pripyat_taynik2">
		<text>Hiding place in Pripyat. There should be three hiding places in Pripyat. One - on the crane. The second - in hotel. The third - in one of apartment houses.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_pripyat_taynik3">
		<text>Hiding place in Pripyat. There should be three hiding places in Pripyat. One - on a tree near road service station. The second - in hotel. The third - in one of apartment houses.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_sacharov">
		<text>Talk to Sakharov about teleport adjustment</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="kostya_meet">
		<text>Meet Bones</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sacharov_pda">
		<text>Sakharov has asked to find PDA Vasilev. From its data it should be in laboratory X-16. It is necessary to search there.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="tex_saharov_pda">
		<text>Sakharov has asked to find PDA Vasilev. From its data it should be in laboratory X-16. It is necessary to search there.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="sacharov_teleport">
		<text>For teleport adjustment the artefact Battery is required. Bring it to Sakharov.</text>
	</string>
