<!-- TB3D 1.0.9.9.9.9 -->
<string id="agr_find_ghost_descr">
<text>... I learned that one of Strelok's group is called Ghost. Though some kind of hook. If I can find Ghost, I can find Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_journal_cache">
<text>Well the cache gave me a further direction of search. I found a stick, which the group used, as a "logbook". Posts there were little, but enough to understand - in the Strelok group, except for himself, were two others: Ghost and Fang. Mention was made of a certain "mutual friend", but whether he was part of the group is unknown. But the fact that he provided substantial assistance to the Strelok group - a fact. Further, according to Ghost, Fang died when they were ambushed. So, while we have the name of one person who knows exactly where Strelok is - Ghost. Finally something concrete. Judging from the correspondence, I really need to look in the northern part of the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_journal_krot">
<text>Well meeting with Mole was productive, perhaps hiding the group - is a reality, and it is found in the catacombs of the Agricultural Industry ... To be the way to the cave. What awaits me there..  who knows ... Hopefully, this cache will hold the secret ...</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_krot_secret_info">
<text>Mole: "... down the winding stairs to the room with columns, then to exit, get into a big room with the pipes on the ceiling. From there down to the second exit, go out into the tunnel and turn left. At the end of the course will be on the right. There, a small room, cross it and turn right. We are looking at the left wall of the hole, near the inscription "Do not climb - kill!". This is the entrance to Strelok's hiding place.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_krot_secret_info_name">
<text>Cache Strelok</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_military_case">
<text>\nReport of the investigation group.\nFor Official Use Only.\nProject Manager "TRUE"\nColonel SBU Kruchelnikovu Vm\nfrom the head of the Search-2 ",\nCaptain Maksimenko DF \n \nMemorandum.\nOur group, consisting of 3 branches of investigators and SWAT SBU from 12.05.2012 to 25.05.2012 conducted surveys of the premises of the former Research Institute of Agriculture on radioactively contaminated soils SRI "Agroprom. Most of the equipment and documents have disappeared in an unknown direction, but even the little that is found, leads to the following conclusion: in the period from 2005 to 2008 Institute to research on my profile was not engaged. All of the results of his "works", received by the Ministry of Agriculture, fabricated. At the same time, getting under the state program funding, equipment and consumables management Institute, represented by Dr. Peter Strizh Danilovich, the fake invoices can forward all this in a laboratory X-18 under the guise of conducting experiments at the farm of the Institute. Apparently, using the code name taken from a group of people passing on the case, since the laboratory with similar numbers in our database. Based on the analysis of retrieved documents can be assumed that it is within an hour drive from the Institute Agroprom. Most likely it is to deep-clandestine laboratories, therefore propose to connect it to search our analytical department. What did this lab, to understand the information available is not possible. In the found documents it is unaware of Professor Chubko and mentions a certain group. In my opinion, this time we found the end of the thread and the analytical department will be at a loose end.\n \nAnnex zipped file with overhead transmission supplies and equipment in some part-time farm of the Institute and an excerpt from the correspondence Strizh Chubko.\n \nCaptain Maksimenko DF 26.05.2012\nProf. Chubko VM From the head of the Institute of Agricultural Sciences Agroprom Doctors Strizh PD Hello, Vadim Mikhailovich, as we agreed, sending in our experimental farm another batch of supplies and equipment for your much needed for agricultural experiments. Financing of the experiments I conducted as field experiments on the topics of our institute, so that the Ministry will be no problems. How are experiments? I still am impressed that you showed me last time. Sincerely yours, PD Swift D. Yes. Mr. Swift PD Much obliged, Peter Danilovich, all received. My boys delighted with the laser spectrometer, if not for you, I would have punched through their long this model. But the Ministry of agriculture, of course, be grateful to get our results ... amused the old man. Experiments run its course and what you saw last time, pales in comparison with what we have already achieved. Rushes often - always glad to see you. Moreover, the drive to "our experimental farm" as you put it, you drive an hour, not more. Yes forgot, I have news for you - the following Monday, I will discuss your candidacy with the Panel. I think they will support me. Sincerely, Prof. Chubko Vm\nProf. Chubko VM From the head of the Institute of Agricultural Sciences Agroprom Doctors Strizh PD Vadim Mikhailovich, thank you for your confidence. I am touched and try to justify it. Participate in a similar experiment, I think every scientist dreams, and if I take a group, I'll be very happy. Sincerely yours, PD Swift P.S. I knocked at the Ministry, two of the latest Japanese broadband oscilloscope and sent them to you with the first shipped over.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_military_case_name">
<text>Report investigative team</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_nii_security_plan">
<text>The scheme marked patrols, guards, towers. On the third floor of the Institute staff. Where documents are stored. Day of the territory patrolled by fully. Night patrols less. After eleven in the evening is a change of the guard, this time in the main house is mostly empty. If you want to climb to the base, then through the gate will not get through, the real way - through the catacombs.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_nii_security_plan_name">
<text>Map-scheme of Research Institute</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_rats_n_soldiers_text">
<text>Military pestering rats that crawl out of sewers. Guilty of war sent to collectors.</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_task_case">
<text>Trader: "As soon as you get the case with the documents from the Agroprom base, Take it to the bartender. He runs the affairs of a stalker bar "100 RADS" by the former factory in Rostock"</text>
</string>
<string id="article_agr_krot_sos">
<text>SOS, the military are cutting down us STALKERs, you guys, all who hear me - help!</text>
</string>
<string id="article_agr_krot_sos_name">
<text>Meeting with Mole</text>
</string>
<string id="article_agr_krot_sos1">
<text>Mole: "Help. We will all be killed!"</text>
</string>
<string id="st_operation_agroprom">
<text>Operation "Agroprom"</text>
</string>
<string id="storyline_gunslinger_flash_info">
<text>Obtained from Ghost:\n \nStrelok, I have bad news. Fang died. We waited in the village near the warehouses. And as we waited, Troy, by referring the usual neutrals. Fang sensed them somehow. You know that feeling from him that it was necessary. Two, we had stopped - apparently punks, but the third turned out to be smarter, sat with 100 meter chasers. In general, there is no more Fang. So the next time we'll go together to the Center. And another thing ... from these two our description was. I'll never know exactly who we ordered. Although in general, many teeth we have. Third, I missed it. In my opinion - one of the mercenaries. On the face of a strong scar. Eyes bright. I'll try to find it.\nSuch are the cases. Be alert and Good Luck.\nGhost\n \nGhost ...\n \nHealthy buddy.\nleaves you old. The link does not go out. I noticed the surveillance.\nDude, I went to the North ... to where we were ... I'll try to slip alone ... I'm sorry, but there is no time to wait for you ... Then explain.\nBut that freak who killed Fang will regret being born ... The slit my belt ... You find out who he is, but I'll be back soon - We'll look.\nOccurs in our common friend. You know what and where at.:)\nGood Luck.\nStrelok\n \nSpit.\n \nHello. Was. You did not find him. You should not have a single to center off. However, it is theirs. Who and where to look for you know.\nGhost</text>
</string> 