<?xml version= "1.0" encoding = "windows-1252"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.4  removed replace - with _, removed "string_table" - aleks1970 -->

<string id="Military">
	<text>Military</text>
	</string>

<string id="Army">
	<text>Army</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_military_army">
<text>\nThe Ukrainian government maintains the Zone's perimeter through troops of it's State Security Service operating under the auspices of it's Ministry of Internal Affairs. The primary role of the military is securing the borders of the Zone, to prevent both unauthorized excursions by stalkers and distribution of artifacts to the outside world without government supervision. While the Military initially possessed a strong presence within the Zone itself, following the Zone's expansion and the subsequent annihilation of military personnel present there, further incursions into the zone were put on indefinite hold. In practice they are one of the most corrupt organizations operating within the Zone, shooting stalkers for sport, extorting them for money, and/or ignoring smuggling operations in exchange for bribes...\n \nSpetsnaz or 'Ukrainian Special Purpose Regiments' are elite Special Forces units that are deployed into The Zone in order to conduct rescue operations, surgical strikes, and other special assignments for the Ukrainian State Security Service. The Spetsnaz are the equivalent in terms of experience to Exoskeleton-wearing Expert Stalkers in the Zone, and although they lack the protection that Exoskeletons provide, Spetsnaz possess superior training, advanced weaponry, and numerical advantage, being most often deployed in squad- or platoon-level formations. Spetsnaz may also employ aerial and mechanised support in the form of Mi-24 Hind Gunships and BTR-70 APCs...</text>
	</string>

<string id="Milstalkers">
	<text>Military S.T.A.L.K.E.R.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_military_milstalkers">
<text>\nSoldiers who underwent special training following their service in the Zone or S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s who voluntarily signed a contract with the Army. Usually equipped with various support gear and well-armed. Used mainly to study the causes and effects of the catastrophe and to map out the Zone. They can work on their own or in small detachments of up to five people. Military S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s do not allow normal S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s to approach and open fire on sight. These men represent some of the most valuable assets the Military possesses in the Zone, as they are highly skilled in combat, and are well-versed in the ways of The Zone...</text>
	</string>


<string id="Social">
	<text>Factions</text>
	</string>

<string id="Bandits">
	<text>Bandits</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_bandits">
<text>\nMembers of the criminal underworld who came to the Zone for different reasons: to make money by selling artifacts, hide from the law or trade in weapons. The Zone is full of bandits, ranging from common thugs to serious criminals, most of whom are members of one gang or another. Although the Zone gangs frequently fight among themselves, the criminal element still poses a serious problem for normal S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s ...</text>
	</string>

<string id="Duty">
	<text>Duty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_duty">
<text>\nA paramilitary group known for its discipline, whose members live according to a strict code. Duty members are the only group to refuse to trade unique items from the Zone with the outside world. According to rumors, all artifacts found by the group are passed on to scientists. Its members consider protecting the outside world from the Zone's dangers their primary objective. Most of the group's operations concern destroying monsters, hence Duty raids often save normal stalkers from serious trouble. The faction has long been at war with Freedom.</text>
	</string>

<string id="Freedom">
	<text>Freedom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_freedom">
<text>\nAnarchists and daredevils who declare themselves fighters for a free access to the Zone and consequently find themselves in constant conflict with the army, military S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s and the Duty faction. These so-called "freedom-fighters" believe in sharing all information about the Zone with the rest of the world and challenge the state's monopoly over the Zone's secrets and wonders.</text>
	</string>

<string id="Killers">
	<text>Mercenaries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_killers">
<text>\nThe most clandestine and secretive faction in the Zone; some don't even believe in it's existence. There are those who regularly use Mercenary services as they are truly professionals, able to quickly deal with any S.T.A.L.K.E.R. and even annihilate a small group of opponents. Their services do not come cheap - the Mercs demand a king's ransom for their services in money or artifacts. The location of their base remains a secret, suggesting that it is deep inside the Zone.</text>
	</string>

<string id="Loners">
	<text>Loners</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_loners">
<text>\nS.T.A.L.K.E.R.s that aren't from any main faction, and the name usually applies to smaller 'packs' of S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s .. They are neutral individuals, and most will trade or offer various missions. It can be assumed that other 'Loners' live a similar life. Their main rival Factions are 'Bandits' and the 'Military'. They are also hostile towards the 'Mercenaries' and the 'Monolith' .. although there are few encounters between either. They are neutral to the 'Freedom', 'Duty' and Scientific' factions. Whilst not a proper faction of their own as per se, killing a Loner will earn the enmity of every other Loner in the  Zone, as word spreads quickly among this nomadic group, and they don't take kindly to murderers...</text>
	</string>

<string id="Monolith">
	<text>Monolith</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_monolith">
<text>\nThis group displays many features of a religious sect. Its members believe in the existence of a complex alien crystal, the Monolith, located somewhere in the center of the Zone. Most S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s treat Monolith adepts with contempt and consider them as lunatics. From its inception the group strives to block all progress towards the center of the Zone, protecting the Monolith from other S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s. Rumor has it that the group has a large base deep in the Zone, but its exact location is know only to it's members...</text>
	</string>

	
<string id="Scientists">
	<text>Scientists</text>
	</string>

<string id="Mobile_groups">
	<text>Research Groups</text>
	</string>

<string id="enc_social_scientists_mobile_groups">
	<text>Mobile Science Group</text>
	</string>

<string id="Mobile_labs">
	<text>Mobile Science Lab</text>
	</string>

	<string id="enc_social_scientists_mobile_labs">
<text>\nMobile Laboratories resemble a small, armored bunker with tiny tinted windows made of hazard-proof glass. The lab is capable of withstanding a lot of damage and with its reliable life-support systems it can work autonomously for several months. The bunker is delivered into the Zone by a transport helicopter. The lab staff never allow visitors past the external air-lock chamber, so no stalker has ever been inside one.</text>
	</string>


<string id="Zomstalkers">
	<text>Zombified S.T.A.L.K.E.R.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_zomstalkers">
<text>\nPoor souls subjected to prolonged exposure in Yantar and a few other heavily radiated sectors. Careless S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s gone mad and turned into walking corpses. Many such corpses wander the Zone, some wander as far as the perimeter. They are beyond help because the destructive process is irreversible. Zombified S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s are still able to use their weapons, but they are quite dumb and can be heard mumbling meaningless, fragmented sentences to themselves. They gradually lose all their skills and turn into zombies. They are usually very aggressive and can present a serious threat in large numbers.</text>
	</string>


<string id="Stalker_clans">
	<text>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Clans</text>
	</string>
	
<string id="lastdays">
	<text>"Last Day"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_social_stalker_clans_lastday">
<text>\nLast Day - One of the first, and once the most powerful Faction in the Zone, consisting of local residents, scientists and all those who remained in the exclusion zone after the Chernobyl accident. For a long time regarded themselves as the only legitimate inhabitants of the Zone, jealously guarding it against any outsiders. It is aggressively tuned to the majority of clans and factions. With its collection of goals considered "gifts" of the Zone and its protection from any abuse and research. It is known that about 2 years ago stalker named Ghost eliminated the leader of the clan, after which the group quickly fell apart, and not being able to choose their leader. Many have joined other groups. Currently, according to unconfirmed information, the clan was restored. It includes former leading scientists of the so-called O-consciousness of the masters of the Monolith factions that have not been religious fanaticism, settled in the area of mercenaries and killers, and some of the local old-timers. According to rumor - the clan has a serious communication outside the perimeter of the Zone, its fighters are well trained and equipped, and skillfully using the gifts of the scientists in the Zone of their achievements and especially the military. The objectives of its size and location of the headquarters - is unknown. In this clan of highly developed intelligence network at the expense of former militants who settled in other groups.</text>
	</string>
