<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.0.9.9.9.8 added af_izomorf -->
<!-- Added missing "enc_zone_izomorf_kompas" from russian with google translate aleks1970 -->
<!-- removed new lines in two diaogs, fixed izomorph crystal and compass, removed '-' -->
<string_table>

    <!--======================================-->
	<!--   INFORMATION REGARDING THE ZONE	  -->
	<!--======================================-->
	<string id="Zone">
		<text>the ZONE</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Zone_story">
		<text>History of the ZONE</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story_2006">
		<text>April 12th, 2006 @ 15:37 hrs...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_zone_story_story_2006">
		<text>The Contaminated Zone was aglow with the brightest of lights, almost unbearable to the human eye. You could virtually see the clouds in the sky turning into vapor. After a moment of dead silence there came rattling thunder, and then the earth shook. People fell to the ground, screwing up their eyes and covering their ears. Those who could still stand ran for their lives. It looked as though all the nuclear fuel buried under the Sarcophagus had suddenly exploded. The next day the Army cordoned off the new Zone..\nThe satellites helped to establish that the epicenter of the explosion was not actually in the vicinity of the NPP reactors, but about half a kilometer away. It is believed that the personnel employed at the Station died instantly...\nThough many people still remained within the cordoned area. The rescue operation soon proved a pointless endeavor, as all the people and machinery sent deep into the area would die or malfunction immediately. A little while after the disaster, the Zone diameter hopped out by a few more kilometers. Most of the government troops guarding the border line and the research teams stationed there perished instantly. Panic stricken, people took to flight. The residents of nearby towns and villages were hastily evacuated. An enormous danger is looming over the world and we can only guess what its full impact may be...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story_2008">
		<text>2008</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_zone_story_story_2008">
		<text>Two years have passed since the second major disaster inside the contaminated Zone surrounding the Chernobyl Nuclear Powewr Plant .. The continuously growing death-toll, countless missing persons, dead cattle, decaying buildings, and maimed forests continues to grow in numbers daily, with no signs of ending soon. Until this day, Scientists have no explanation as to what exactly happened in at the NPP .. Meanwhile .. countless Anomalies were discovered in the area, and the Zone continues to expand as each day passes...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story_2010">
		<text>2010</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_zone_story_story_2010">
		<text>Following in the tracks of those foolhardy loners that call themselves S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s, Scientific Research expeditions are once again embarking on an in-depth study of the Zone. However, the perimeter once 'guarded' by the Army has sinced gained some other, more dangerous inhabitants .. from common poachers to the worst kind of Bandit scum stemming from the Russian criminal underworld. Most of the S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s roam the Zone in search of Anomalies and the so-called Artefacts they produce .. all in the pursuit of the substantial wealth they promise those foolish enough to pursuue them deep into the heart of the Zone...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Story_raid">
		<text>Break in the Zone ... 2010</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_zone_story_story_raid">
		<text>The Army, including Special Forces Units headed by Paramilitary S.T.A.L.K.E.R. Detachments, launched a massive raid deep into the Zone. Their objective was to break through to the Chernobyl NPP, and wipe out what was believed to be the cause of all of the Anomalous fields throughout the Zone. If not successful, they were to at least obtain first-hand information on the Zone's true 'Source'. This doomed endeavor, involving over a thousand military personnel, was a complete, and utter failure. Isolated groups of survivors were forced to settle within the Zone's perimeter with absolutely no hopes of being rescued anytime soon .. they, like so many others, have simply been forgotten...</text>
	</string>
	<!--======================================-->
	<!--   LOCATIONS THROUGHOUT THE ZONE	  -->
	<!--======================================-->
	<string id="Locations">
		<text>Locations</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Escape">
		<text>the Cordon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_escape">
		<text>Think of it as the Zone's antechamber; it's a good place for Rookies to get their head around. You'll find a Trader named Sidorovich in the vaults at the back of the village, next to the Army Outpost. Don't miss the chance to talk to him. You'd be advised to steer clear of the outpost itself, however. You don't want the Soldiers to catch sight of you - most of them shoot first and don't bother asking questions later. Yet, as always, there are some who can be bribed as long as the top brass is looking the other way. Attacking the soldiers is not recommended, unless they pose a direct threat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Garbage">
		<text>the Dump</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_garbage">
		<text>Nothing but a vast, desolate machinery graveyard .. Right after the first accident, whole heaps of radioactive waste were dumped there. Mostly ruins of old buildings infested with mutants. Much like the outskirts of the Zone, the place is literally swarming with Rookies, with the occasional Bandit loitering about, always on the lookout for careless S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s .. Some common artefacts to be found here, but most of them are just not worth the effort. You'll be better off elsewhere. Going north, you will get to the Wild Territory, East lays the entrance to the Dark Valley, with the road to the Agroprom Research Institute to the West</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Agroprom">
		<text>Agroprom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_agroprom">
		<text>A strange, heavily contaminated area, Agroprom is home to the Agroprom Research Institute and a factory, once connected to the outside world via railroad. It's notable for it's extensive network of underground facilities, corridors and other areas. To the north-west lies a shallow lake, chock full of abandoned equipment and other debris. Following the 1986 incident, the Research Institute was created to analyze the possibilities of agriculture on radiated soil, apparently either as a sister facility to the Dark Valley science center or a replacement for it after the construction site was abandoned</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bar">
		<text>Rostock</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_bar">
		<text>The Duty faction have set up camp on the plain's edge and they always welcome Stalkers in need of rest. A desert oasis of sorts: a place completely devoid of anomalies and mutants. Be sure to check out the 100 Rads Bar in the vaults - it's a meeting point for S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s from all over the Zone. The 100*Rads Bar is operated by the local Trader, so if you're interested in selling or buying wares apart from the local gossip, that's the place to go. North of the Bar is the old Military Base, with the Dump located directly to the South...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Darkdolina">
		<text>Dark Valley</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_darkdolina">
		<text>Always gloomy, always misty, and always rainy. S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s venturing into the Dark Valley are likely to find valuable artefacts, instant death, or both. A place frequented by some of the most experienced old-timers, though you may also stumble upon some common bandits. There's supposed to be an underground lab around there somewhere, so it might be worthwhile to look for a hidden entrance along the way. No one has returned from there alive, though, and no one can tell for sure just what nasty surprises await you there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Military_loc">
		<text>Army Warehouses</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_military_loc">
		<text>A deserted Army Base next to a dilapidated hamlet and a small marsh. The village is an eerie place, literally swarming with mutants - the bloodsuckers alone are legion. S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s do their best to keep away from it, even if it means going extra kilometers around it. The anarchists from the Freedom faction have settled down in the Army base. The road connecting the base to the Zone is guarded by the infamous Brain Scorcher, which blocks the way to Pripyat and the Chernobyl NPP...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Pripiat">
		<text>Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_pripiat">
		<text>Pripyat is a city that used to be home to the Engineers working at the Chernobyl Nuclear Power Plant, and their families. It was evacuated after the incident in 1986, leaving nothing but a ghost town in it's place. When the Zone appeared in 2006, it became an unreachable area because of the infamous 'Brain Scorcher', blocking access to the center of the Zone. In 2011, the Monolith faction marched South through Pripyat, and then beyond .. As a result, Pripyat became heavily populated with Monolith faction members along with a lot of very dangerous mutants that seemed to follow them on their Southern trek...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Radar">
		<text>Radar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_radar">
		<text>Resting in an area dominated by Monolith goons, Zombified Stalkers, Snorks, and a special type of Pseudodog. Loners and members of other factions have also started to enter the area, heading for Pripyat. Bloodsuckers and packs of Blind Dogs tend to populate the road near the entrance to the Military Warehouses. The Red Forest area also contains the DUGA-3 Radar System, which is where the infamous Laboratory X-10 is fabled to be to be .. A dreadful place. Many enter only to vanish without a trace. Many reports of persons going completely insane, and becoming zombiefied. A human shell is all that is left. No one has ever returned from this Hell on Earth...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Rostok">
		<text>Wild Territory</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_rostok">
		<text>The Wild Territory used to be the site of a rather large manufacturing plant, currently in ruins. Many S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s have met their untimely death there, as the place is swarming with all sorts of monsters. The beasts are literally streaming over there from the entire Zone. It is said that something of great importance is hidden at this site, so there are always plenty of daredevils willing to try their luck .. Mercenaries are located in the abandoned construction sites towards Yantar, primarily inhabiting the gutted-out buildings .. as Mercenaries usually carry scoped weapons, they can take pot shots at careless wanderers from a distance, making travelling through this are very problematic...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Stancia">
		<text>Stancia</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_stancia">
		<text>The Chernobyl Nuclear Power Plant is where it all started. In 1986, a reactor meltdown led to nuclear fallout irradiating and rendering hazardous a 30km-wide area now known as the 'Zone'. Following the incident, the Zone was evacuated and the Reactor was sealed in a concrete Sarcophagus. This is the heart of the Zone. If you believe the many legends, this is also the site of the 'Monolith' .. a mysterious thing said to be capable of making any 'one' wish come true...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Yantar_pda_name">
		<text>Yantar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_locations_yantar">
		<text>Yantar wasn't always a swampy, desolate place. A long time ago it was a large lake .. however, its fate was sealed when it was chosen as the perfect location for a factory. The construction crew caused an accident underground and the water drained from the lake, leaving a stinking swamp in it's place. It is not known when the secret Laboratory known simply as X-16 was constructed underneath the factory and it's entirely possible that the factory itself was meant as an elaborate cover for the Lab. What is known, is that after certain scientific breakthroughs in Lab X-18, a prototype Kaymanov Emitter was set up in X-16, with it's massive Antenna system hidden deep inside one of the factory buildings...\nAfter the Zone was born in 2006, the complex fell into disrepair and was abandoned, but the Emitter was still active. This has proven disastrous, as many S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s, lured by the prospect of scavenging an intact factory, fell prey to the Emitter's disastrous influence and became zombified, almost feral creatures extremely aggressive towards anyone, and anything they encounter...\nSometime after the Zone's appearance, the Yantar area was chosen as a prime location for the Mobile Science Lab operated by a Professor Sakharov, and his Ecologists. Their bunker was air-dropped into the swamp under heavy protection of the Ukrainian Military, and they soon after began studying the Zone and it's various inhabitants...</text>
	</string>
	<!--======================================-->
	<!--	  DMX 1.3.2 LOCATIONS			  -->
	<!--======================================-->
	
	<!-- duplicated string id's was moved in to the "dmx_mod_encyclopedia.xml" file - aleks1970 -->

	<!--======================================-->
	<!--   	         ANOMALIES				  -->
	<!--======================================-->
	<string id="Anomalies">
		<text>Anomalies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Bald">
		<text>Springboard</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_bald">
		<text>One of the first anomalies ever recorded - an unstable gravitational field inflicting shock damage to anyone within its radius. Remains active for a week on average. The amount of damage inflicted changes during its lifetime, ranging from minor bruises, through serious wounds, to instant death. Easy to spot in daylight. Accompanied by air fluctuation above the anomaly, dancing leaves and distinctive crimson-colored stains on the ground. Picked up by all types of detectors, the Springboard can also be revealed by throwing objects into it. Forms three kinds of Artefacts: Medusa, Stone Flower, and Night Star...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Electra">
		<text>Elektra</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_electra">
		<text>An anomalous formation, roughly 10 meters in diameter, accumulating large quantities of static electricity. When triggered, the anomaly bursts out in dozens of miniature lightnings, causing electric shock nearly always lethal to all living beings. Recognizable by the bluish fog hovering above it in daylight. At nighttime, the Elektra can be revealed using any type of detector or by throwing metal objects into the anomaly. Forms three types of Artefacts: Sparkler, Flash and Moonlight...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fuzz">
		<text>Fuzz</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_fuzz">
		<text>One of the Zone's examples of mutated vegetation. Reacts to rapidly approaching living beings by discharging a cloud of projectiles severely injuring uncovered or lightly protected skin upon contact. Does not react to slowly moving targets. Forms three types of artifacts (possibly its seeds): Thorn, Crystal Thorn and Urchin...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Gravi">
		<text>Vortex</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_gravi">
		<text>An anomaly of presumably gravitational nature. When triggered, the tremendous power of the Vortex drags everything within the radius of 10-15 meters towards center. Victims drawn into the core have no chance of survival: their bodies are quickly constricted into a tight lump, only to be blown up in a powerful discharge of energy a moment later. The anomaly remains stationary throughout its lifetime (a week on average). Easily recognizable in daylight by the air fluctuation above, dancing leaves, fragments of dismembered corpses lying around and a distinctive dark stain in the center. Highly dangerous at night since it can be revealed only by means of a detector or by throwing metal objects into it. Forms three types of artifacts: Wrenched, Gravi and Goldfish...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_izomorf">
		<text>"General concepts"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_izomorf">
		<text>Izomorfy (monolidy)-alien education, which are a combination of energy and special forms crystals of rare elements – lantanoidov and actinides that are being introduced into the world of the zone of peace have different views and the Monolith features. They can be in the form of capsules or artifacts or be like a normal bandage or a pack of cartridges. Some of them-the so-called "Blind izomorfy" - in the Zone do not possess "visible" qualities and features and are only detector izomorfov, but their presence in the area can lead to the most unexpected consequences. Learn about the properties of the other izomorfov is possible only after direct contact - hanging on the belt or on the rucksack. Positive properties and negative monolidy are United by one common property - their effect lasts from several hours to several days. It is likely that in the zone they were formed under the influence of an alien energy flows, flows which were opened after the explosion at the Chernobyl nuclear power plant and generators and operates on different substances - especially for metals, crystals and artifacts. While izomorfy are in the area - You cannot create a balance of two mutually opposite energy fields. Through some portals you can send monolidy to another dimension - the so-called "Zamonolite", and in return receive a wide variety of subjects, sometimes quite useless for a man or any information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Lift">
		<text>Lift</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_lift">
		<text>A relatively harmless anomaly, temporarily negating normal gravity. Manifests itself as an area - usually several meters in diameter - where Earth's gravitational pull is greatly reduced. This anomaly has been known to form the Pellicle artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mono">
		<text>Radiation Cloud</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_monolit">
		<text>Radiation Cloud, nicknamed by inhabitants of the Monolith Zone. It is named so because of a unusual luminescence, color and the form reminding, on hearings, a legendary Monolith - the Executor of desires. Possesses strongly pronounced psi-influence and the raised radiating background. At hit in an operative range of anomaly the person has a strong dizziness, there comes a desorientation in space, except for it{this} there is a strong irradiation... The Radius of action depends on force of anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zhar">
		<text>Heat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_zhar">
		<text>While inactive, the anomaly manifests itself as a barely visible cloud of hot air. When triggered by an object or a living being it instantly heats up to lethal temperatures approaching 1500K. At nighttime, it can be revealed by powerful detectors or by throwing metal objects into the trigger area. Forms three types of artifacts: Droplets, Fireball and Crystal...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="smallrain1">
		<text>Fog</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_smallrain1">
		<text>Visually, this anomaly resembles a low, white fog which lies close to the ground. The origins of this anomaly are unknown. It is made up of a lethal mixture of poisonous gases. Contact with these gaseous emissions will immediately cause burning, and irritation both external, as well as internal. If inhaled for more than a few seconds, it will cause suffocation, leading to complete closure of the lungs, and soon after.... Death.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sphere">
		<text>Bubble</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_sphere">
		<text>The anomaly simply known as Bubble looks like a transparent hemisphere. Possibly a subspecies of the Elektra anomaly, and differs from it in that once the Bubble has reacted, or expelled it's electrical energy, it dissipates and no longer poses any further threat. The Bubble possesses the unique ability to envelop, and keep objects within their own environment. Sometimes this environment is separated from the basic anomaly and will be transformed to the subspecies Teleport anomaly, and will take on the shape, and form of a proper shere...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zavesa">
		<text>Tornado</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_zavesa">
		<text>When at rest, the Tornado is hardly discernable on the ground in the form of two spinning, grey funnels of air. When within 5 meters, vision becomes impaired and orientation is affected. Once fully activated, it will cause significant damage to anything caught within it's 15 to 20 meter radius, lifting it into the air, and spinning it violently for a short duration of time. The Tornado does not last long, but causes significant damage  during it's life-cycle. If caught inside one, and somehow managing to survive, it causes serious bleed-out as a result of severe internal hemorrhaging...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="fountain">
		<text>Fountain</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_fountain">
		<text>Similar in appearance to a natural water fountain - and sounding like one as well. Not to be trusted as such, however .. as this anomaly can cause significant damage to anyone unfortunate enough to have gotten too close to it. Emits a powerful burst of anomolous electricity which can deal serious amounts of damage. A very deceiving entity .. as most of it's presence is sub-terrainian, and can span far beyond it's apparent size; making it even more dangerous than it seems to be .. Can cause severe damage to Armour, and inflicts severe bleeding...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="xvatalka">
		<text>Xvatalka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_xvatalka">
		<text>Xvatalka grasps it's victims by means of chutes that protrude from it's centre and holds them there, helpless whilst inflicting damage in the form of severe bleeding. Anything caught in the center is slowed down, thus allowing for more serious, prolonged damage to take place. Belonging to a class of bio-anomalies, It is believed that it is some kind of foliage which has been mutated by the Zone's unstable influence by any number of other sub-terrainian anomalies .. As they do remain stationary, hiding in the grass, awaiting it's victims, it is possible to mark their location on the map located inside the PDA. It can also be picked up by the Advanced Detector...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zvezda">
		<text>Star</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_zvezda">
		<text>An anomaly of unknown origins. On contact, it inflicts injuries similar to the effects of a strong acid. It is Extremely dangerous, as it waits underground and, as such it is invisible. It attacks suddenly, and without warning, emanating with a greenish luminescence an area of up to 10 meters., paralizing it's victim. These attacks are almost always fatal, and depend on the duration of exposure. The Star anomaly can be picked up by means of an Elite Detector... Forms three types of artifacts: Slime, Slug, and Mica...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="smoke">
		<text>Smoke</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_smoke">
		<text>A cloud of a smoke containing an unknown organic poison. This type of anomaly is initially formed by a small cloud of a grey smoke, which, at first contact with it's victim very quickly increases in volume, considerably reducing visibility and inflicting damage of various types... the first of which is minor bleeding and asthma, to which a Gas-Mask is of little or no help at all. Only a Protective Suit with a fully independent air circulation system will help. The gas contained in this anomaly is capable of penetrating through even the mosty dense materials because of the minute size of it's particles. Thankfully, encounters with the Smoke anomaly are few, and far between...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="emi">
		<text>EMI</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_emi">
		<text>Scientific reports show that the EMI anomaly is basically a localized Electro-Magnetic Impulse formed in the wake of an Emission. Often found alongside high-voltage power lines, scrap metal heaps, and other man-made constructions; found both above, and below ground. Causes serious damage both to organic entities, and technical equipment. Effects are: dizziness, nausea, disorientation, and eventually seizures induced by the strong Electro-Magnetic Impulse. Luckily for S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s, there is a short period of time to escape the anomaly before the Impulse is fully charged, and generated...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Meat">
		<text>Whirligig</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_meat">
		<text>The anomaly snatches its victims up in the air and spins them at a breakneck speed. The exact nature of the Whirligig remains unknown. The anomaly can be recognized by a light whirlwind of dust above and by body fragments scattered in the vicinity. Victims caught on its outer rim - far enough from the maximum effect zone at the center - can escape the Whirligig with relatively minor injuries. Forms three types of artefacts: Stone Blood, Meat Chunk and Soul...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Radioactive">
		<text>Radiation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_radioactive">
		<text>Radioactive contamination can enter the body through ingestion, inhalation, absorption, or injection. For this reason, it is important to use personal protective equipment when working within an irradiated Zone or with radioactive artefacts. Radioactive contamination may also be ingested as the result of eating contaminated plants and animals or drinking contaminated water or milk from exposed animals. Following a major contamination incident, all potential pathways of internal exposure should be considered... Like many other releases of radioactivity into the environment, the Chernobyl release was controlled by the physical and chemical properties of the radioactive elements in the core. While the general population often perceives plutonium as a particularly dangerous nuclear fuel, its effects are almost eclipsed by those of its fission products. Particularly dangerous are highly radioactive compounds that accumulate in the food chain, such as some isotopes of iodine and strontium.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Time_pda_name">
		<text>Time Machine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_time">
		<text>A true miracle of an anomaly: an area several meters in diameter where the time flow is significantly slower than usual. Appears to have no negative effect on human health. However, the Time Machine can be very difficult to get out of. Interestingly, removing Mama's Beads - an artefact usually found in the center of the anomaly - causes the Time Machine to disappear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Vapour">
		<text>Vapour</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_smallrain">
		<text>The Vapour anomaly has a greater density than air, so it tends to settle near the ground. When it gets cold, the gas becomes a liquid which leaches back into the ground. Heat makes it transform back into a gas that spreads rapidly near the ground. One of the reasons that this gas is so toxic is that it is highly reactive with water in the mucous membranes of the lungs and eyes. This leads to the production of hydrochloric acid and hypochlorous acid, which together act as an eye and lung irritant, corroding tissue. There is no antidote for exposure to Vapour, so it is best to be avoided..</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Pulsar">
		<text>Pulsar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_pulsar">
		<text>The oscillating electric and magnetic fields emanating from the Pulsar anomaly will induce an electric current in any conductor through which it passes. Strong radiation can induce current capable of delivering an electric shock to both humans as well as animals. It can also overload and destroy electrical equipment. The induction of currents by oscillating magnetic fields is also the way in which solar storms disrupt the operation of electrical and electronic systems, causing damage to and even the explosion of power distribution transformers, blackouts, and interference with electromagnetic signals [radio, TV, and PDA signals] ..  Extremely high power electromagnetic radiation can cause electric currents strong enough to create electrical arcs when an induced voltage exceeds the breakdown voltage of the surrounding air. These sparks can then ignite flammable materials or gases, possibly leading to an explosion...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="Fruit Punch">
		<text>Fruit Punch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_ameba">
		<text>The Fruit Punch anomaly is a puddle of greenish, blue, and golden lambent liquid that is easily visible throughout the Zone. On contact with organic matter, the Fruit Punch lights up brightly and emits a sharp hissing sound. It is extremely corrosive, damaging anything that touches it instantly upon contact. Any object left within the Fruit Punch anomaly will eventually dissolve, hinting at the anomaly's basic acidic nature, and possible chemical origins...</text>
	</string>
	<!--======================================-->
	<!--		     ARTEFACTS				  -->
	<!--======================================-->
	<string id="Artifacts">
		<text>Artefacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_electro_crystal_thorn">
		<text>Crystal Thorn (Elecktra)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_electro_crystal_thorn_s">
		<text>Crystal Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_electro_crystal_thorn">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+3\n%c[default]Extremely rare artefact possessing positive properties. It is formed in the Elektra anomaly from standard coal in conditions of full darkness. Found only in underground vaults, and is practically unknown throughout the Zone. Considerably accelerates metabolism, therefore it is important not to forget to have sustainance close at hand... It should demand a good price, but since hardly anyone knows of it's existence; finding a prospective buyer could prove itself to be difficult, if not impossible...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_water_flower">
		<text>Water Flower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artifact_af_water_flower">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+3\n%c[default]Strange artefact of unknown origin. Only one of these strange artefacts has ever been found, and it was right after repeated explosions near the Generators. It is physically quite beautiful, possessing a bluish luminescence. Quickly accelerates metabolism, providing extra energy in difficult situations. The drawback to this, of course is the need for constant nourishment in order to feed this metabolism. Slightly radioactive. Unconfirmed Data: - can be used as part of the transmutation recipe for the Heart of the Poltergeist...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_water_flower1">
		<text>Purple Flower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artifact_af_water_flower1">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+10\n%c[default]Upon interaction with the Heart of the Poltergeist artefact, the Water Flower loses a small part of it's energy, and changes it's appearance to that of this attractive new Artefact... the Purple Flower...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_kamen_udachy">
		<text>Success Stone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artifact_af_kamen_udachy">
		<text>Hyperabsolute. Artefact, which is probably only possible to find only once in a lifetime, given the extreme rarity of components and other conditions of transmutation. Cluster of huge amounts of energy and vitality, many times reducing radiation. Maybe as a one-time, so probably the gradual use of the properties of the artefact. The price for this hyperabsolute is purely symbolic, since the possibility of obtaining this artifact know only one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_spiral">
		<text>Spiral</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_af_spiral">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1 ]_______ %c[255,255,255,255] Radiation%c[255,255,1,1] +7\n%c[default] The product of an experiment gone wrong by a Dr. Klenow... became the first known synthesized Artefact. Shaped like a spiral, it has some very useful properties. However, there are also negative. Far removed in appearance and properties from the original, from which a copy is made, but given the positive qualities and having the presence of artefacts, offsetting the negative side - can be very useful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_eye_voron">
		<text>Raven's Eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_af_eye_voron">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1 ]_______ %c[255,255,255,255] Radiation%c[255,255,1,1] +10\n%c[default] Unusual and rare artefact that looks like a luminous sphere, which is located on a branch. Very Rare. According to unconfirmed reports, it is believed to have been produced by the EMI anomaly when reacting with a certain type of wood, at least, this artefact is sometimes found in the area of this anomaly. Emits radiation, and reduces protection from bullet wounds, However, it also possesses a number of very positive qualities. Both beautiful, as well as expensive...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_ameba_mica">
		<text>Mica</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_ameba_mica_s">
		<text>Mica</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_ameba_mica">
		<text>The Fruit Punch anomaly is able to create such an artefact at the rarest, most extreme collection of physical conditions. The result is a semi-transparent, hard object. When worn on the belt, this artefact will coagulate the blood from wounds, thus dereasing the amount of blood loss. However, the chances of receiving damage from burns is increased. This artefact is of great interest to Scientific Organizations in and around the Zone. A rare and expensive artefact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_ameba_slime">
		<text>Slime</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_ameba_slime_s">
		<text>Slime</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_ameba_slime">
		<text>It is certain that this artefact is created by the anomaly called Fruit Punch. When worn on the belt, this artefact will coagulate the blood from wounds, thus dereasing the amount of blood loss. However, the chances of receiving damage from burns is increased. This artefact is of moderate interest to Scientific Organizations in and around the Zone. A common and inexpensive artefact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_ameba_slug">
		<text>Slug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_ameba_slug_s">
		<text>Slug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_ameba_slug">
		<text>Formed by the Fruit Punch anomaly. The negative qualities of this artifact are compensated by the fact that it heightens the coagulation quality of blood. However, the chances of receiving damage from burns is increased. This artefact is highly sought after by Scientific Organizations in and around the Zone. It's not often that one encounters such a rare artefact, and Traders will pay well for it too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_blood">
		<text>Stone Blood</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_blood_s">
		<text>Stone Blood</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_blood">
		<text>Artefact formed in the Whirligig anomaly. It is an ugly reddish colour, pressed and fancifully curved polymerized residues of plants, soil and bones. When wearing an artifact on your belt, a kind of mysterious way, slightly faster healing of wounds and stops bleeding. Do stalkers is believed that this artifact lies the power of people who perished in the anomaly. However, this artifact attracts predators to the owner. Selling price is low due to a fairly wide distribution. Interest in the artifact exhibit scientific organizations, primarily doctors and all sorts of religious cults.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_cristall">
		<text>Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_cristall_s">
		<text>Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_cristall">
		<text>This artefact is formed in anomalous zones with intense thermal activity. Actively consumes excessive heat, remaining cool to the touch throughout. This artefact is created when heavy metals fall into the "Burner" anomaly. This artefact eliminates radiation wonderfully. It is highly valued by S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s and quite difficult to find. Demands a high price, and is of great interest within Scientific Organizations throughout the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_cristall_flower">
		<text>Stone Flower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_cristall_flower_s">
		<text>Stone Flower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_cristall_flower">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+5\n%c[default]Born in the Springboard anomaly, this artefact is made up of a granite-like stone deformed by an extreme gravitational force, resulting in a crystallized formation that has not been explained by science to date. Can provide moderate protection against bullets, and is slightly radioactive. The bits of metallic compounds create a beautiful light play. It is very calming to study this artefact at night by the fire.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_drops">
		<text>Droplet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_drops_s">
		<text>Droplet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_drops">
		<text>Artefact produced by the Heat anomaly. Teardrop-shaped formation with a cracked glazed surface. Stalkers say that wearing an artifact reduces damage from the bites of wild beasts. Impairs endurance. The price is low. Interest in the artifact exhibit collectors and jewelers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dummy_battery">
		<text>Battery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dummy_battery_s">
		<text>Battery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_dummy_battery">
		<text>the Origin of an artefact is not known. Ridge brilliant education. Very useful artefact for its{his} carrier{bearer}. Improves all characteristics of radiating stability{resistance} and a susceptibility to an electricity. The impression is made, that the artefact strengthens any processes proceeding around of it{him}. The price of sale huge. Special interest to an artefact is shown with the scientific organizations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dummy_dummy">
		<text>Dummy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dummy_dummy_s">
		<text>Dummy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_dummy_dummy">
		<text>the Origin of an artefact is not known. Two rigid disks linked together by slime. The artefact slightly reduces defeat from all types of gravitational anomalies and explosions, absorbing shock waves. The price of sale high. Interest to an artefact is shown with the scientific organizations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dummy_glassbeads">
		<text>Mama's Beads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dummy_glassbeads_s">
		<text>Mama's Beads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_dummy_glassbeads">
		<text>Shaped like a DNA helix, the beads are created in the Burner anomaly and pulsate, generating emissions beneficial to the human body. These emissions increase the metabolism of any living creature, accelerating clotting and healing of open wounds. The exact mechanism behind this artifact continues to puzzle Scientists. An extremely rare artefact: it has no negative qualities. Scientists have never been able to duplicate it under laboratory conditions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dummy_pellicle">
		<text>Pellicle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dummy_pellicle_s">
		<text>Pellicle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_dummy_pellicle">
		<text>According to Professor Sakharov, this was the first artefact the Ecologists managed to create under controlled laboratory conditions. Now, this artefact is so rare that many Researchers can't even imagine that such a substance could even exist at all. Provides excellent protection against caustic chemical components.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dummy_spring">
		<text>Spring</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dummy_spring_s">
		<text>Spring</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_dummy_spring">
		<text>the origin of this rare artefact is unkknown. resembles two rigid disks linked together by viscous slime. According to the opinion of some Scientists, this artefact is a hybrid between the artefacts Battery and Shell. Highly sought after by Zone Scientists, and they will pay good money for it as well...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_electra_flash">
		<text>Flash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_electra_flash_s">
		<text>Flash</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_electra_flash">
		<text>The Elektra anomaly sometimes births this artefact. Thanks to its heavily crystallized molecules, this electrostatic artefact is a powerful absorbent of electric charges, able to protect its bearer from electric shocks of up to 5,000 volts. S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s readily keep it for themselves, rather than trade it because of it's positive qualities. If sold, it goes for a good price, and because it has a nice external appearance, it is highly sought after by Jewellers dealing with Traders from a safe distance outside the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_electra_moonlight">
		<text>Moonlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_electra_moonlight_s">
		<text>Moonlight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_electra_moonlight">
		<text>This unique electrostatic artifact can resonate under the influence of psi-waves. S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s have learned to fine-tune the artefact so that it resonates in opposite phase to the main source of emissions, thus fully or significantly neutralizing their effects. This artefact is formed inside of the Elektra anomaly on rare occasions. It has powerful restorative abilities, but at the cost of electrical resistance. a very rare, and expensive artefact. Highly sought after by members within the Scientific Community, as well as Jewellers, and Collectors.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_caterpillar">
		<text>Plasma Caterpillar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_caterpillar_s">
		<text>Plasma Caterpillar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_caterpillar">
		<text>the Rare artefact. You will not find it{him} in one anomaly as he is an alive biosubstance. It is formed from Bezoar from stomach of old controllers at influence on them anomaly until hot. Time Transmuratsii approximately 5 minutes, probability of successful end with education of the Plasma caterpillar{track} approximately 75%. It is not enough, who in the Zone knows this recipe and existence of the given artefact. People Sakharov assume, that this alive substance is formed of not digested bones of bones of an electrochimera under long influence of the perverted gastric juice of the controller, hypnotic aura constantly surrounding it{him} and the subsequent influence extremely heats. Remains only to guess, as this biomass thus does not perish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_babka_4">
		<text>Grandma's Beads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_babka_4">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]0\n%c[default]the Absolute received by transmutation of an artefact Beads Grandmother Burer in current of 5 minutes in anomaly until hot. The recipe, obviously, has been received by practical consideration. From positive qualities it is necessary to note increase in stability of the owner of an artefact to bullet wounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_arhara_globus">
		<text>Rattle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_arhara_globus_s">
		<text>Rattle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_arhara_globus">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+5\n%c[default]This absolute on appearance is completely not similar to the predecessor, reminds a children's rattle with prickles, whence and its{his} name has gone... Approve{Confirm}, that during transformation play a role of unknown persons to a science of connection of the silver, present in anomaly jellied. Possesses quite good qualities, in spite of the fact that the main feature of its{his} predecessor - protection against psi-influence a little weakened... Moderately radioactive. Has the quite good price.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_part_monolit">
		<text>Heart of the Poltergeist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_part_monolit_s">
		<text>Heart of the Poltergeist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artifact_af_part_monolit">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+85\n%c[default] Heart of the poltergeist the Extremely rare artefact reminding pulsing heart. Actually represents a splinter of a monolith. Whom and when he broke off from the basic part of a crystal it was not known, but the artefact possesses a greater{big} set of positive qualities. Lack only one - the highest doze of radiated radiation. To carry away such artefact it is impossible even at presence of special containers and suits. It becomes possible{probable} only at presence on a belt{zone} of the several artefacts reducing radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_part_monolit1">
		<text>Modified Heart of the Poltergeist</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artifact_af_part_monolit1">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+15\n%c[default] the Modified Heart of the poltergeist . It is received by practical consideration by the professor Maple, tried to make an identical copy of the given artefact. Attempt by success has not crowned. At an artefact properties, but fortunately have changed, the internal structure has not suffered.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_part_monolit2">
		<text>Modified Heart of the Poltergeist II</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artifact_af_part_monolit2">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+15\n%c[default] the Modified Heart of the poltergeist II . At interaction with an artefact the Water Flower, Heart of the Poltergeist accumulated a part of its{his} energy that else has more strengthened its{his} positive qualities.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_zharka">
		<text>Black Energy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_zharka_s">
		<text>Black Energy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_item_zharka_descr">
		<text>Black energy - this artefact has received the name for the dark color. Is a product of several anomalies - such sometimes happens, when at the occurrence different kinds of anomalies adjoin among themselves. As well as cobble-stone, Black energy does not possess any visible positive qualities and consequently does not enjoy authority neither at {unknown}, nor at dealers. Many at all do not take it{him}, including a useless weed. However extremely the little know, that this artefact radiates a specific kind of the energy similar on microwave, that has enabled to use it{him} in some development as a specific element of a dining.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_electra_sparkler">
		<text>Sparkler</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_electra_sparkler_s">
		<text>Sparkler</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_electra_sparkler">
		<text>Artefact produced by the Elektra anomaly. Translucent amorphous formation sometimes found generating small lightning-sparks. Wearing an artifact on your belt slightly increases stamina. The price is low. Interest in the artifact exhibit scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_fireball">
		<text>Fireball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_fireball_s">
		<text>Fireball</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_fireball">
		<text>Artefact produced by the Heat anomaly. Translucent reddish spherical shape. Stalkers say that wearing an artifact reduces damage from the bites of wild beasts. Impairs endurance. Price is average. Interest in the artifact exhibit collectors and jewelers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_fuzz_kolobok">
		<text>Burnt Fuzz</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_fuzz_kolobok_s">
		<text>Burnt Fuzz</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_fuzz_kolobok">
		<text>the Artefact of a unknown origin. Scientists till now cannot solve the recipe of reception of this miracle of the Zone. At carrying on a belt{zone} stability{resistance} of an organism any physical damages considerably{much} increases. It is radioactive. The price very high. Special interest to an artefact is shown by physicians.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_gold_fish">
		<text>Goldfish</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_gold_fish_s">
		<text>Goldfish</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_gold_fish">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+10\n%c[default]Artefact that occasionally formed in the anomaly Vortex. Education with a beautiful mirrored surface. At night, light the space around them within a radius of 1-2 meters. Is a compressed and intricately curved strong gravity remains of plants, soil and anything else that gets in the anomaly at the time of discharge. When wearing the artifact at the waist increases the immunity to shock the gravitational anomalies, such as a Springboard, but this plague, due to powerful gravitational field pulls the bullet that was not pleased with her owner. Selling price is very high. The probability of occurrence - low. Interest in the artifact exhibit scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_gravi">
		<text>Gravi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_gravi_s">
		<text>Gravi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_gravi">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+5\n%c[default]Beautiful artefact formed in the Vortex anomaly. Is a compressed and intricately curved strong gravity remains of plants, soil and anything else that gets in the vicinity of the anomaly. When wearing the artifact at the waist increases the immunity to shock the gravitational anomalies, such as a springboard. Sale price and the probability of occurrence - the average. Interest in the artifact exhibit scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_medusa">
		<text>Medusa</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_medusa_s">
		<text>Medusa</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_medusa">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+3\n%c[default]Artifact formed in the anomaly Springboard.  Is a compressed and intricately curved strong gravity remains of plants, soil and anything else that gets in the vicinity of the anomaly. When wearing the artifact at the waist increases the immunity to retractor gravitational anomalies, such as the funnel and Medusa and has little effect shield which reduces damage from small arms. Slightly radioactive. Selling price is low due to a fairly wide distribution. Interest in the artifact exhibit scientific organizations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_mincer_meat">
		<text>Meat Chunk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_mincer_meat_s">
		<text>Meat Chunk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_mincer_meat">
		<text>Artifact formed in the Whirligig anomaly. It is an ugly yellowish formation of pressed and fancifully curved polymerized residues of plants, soil and bones. When wearing an artifact on your belt, a kind of mystical way, greatly speeds up the healing and well-stops bleeding. Do stalkers is believed that this artifact lies the power of people who perished in the anomaly. However, this artifact attracts predators to the owner. Sale price and the probability of occurrence - the average. Interest in the artifact exhibit scientific organizations, primarily doctors and all sorts of religious cults.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_night_star">
		<text>Night Star</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_night_star_s">
		<text>Night Star</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_night_star">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+10\n%c[default]Artefact that occasionally forms inside the Springboard anomaly .. Education with a beautiful mirrored surface and colored phosphorescent inclusions. At night, light greenish light all around him in a radius of 1-2 meters, for which he received from stalkers name. Is a compressed and intricately curved strong gravity remains of plants, soil and anything else that gets in the vicinity of the anomaly. When wearing an Artefact on the belt greatly increases the immunity to gravitational anomalies, such as the Vortex and Whirligig, and also has the effect of reducing damage from small arms. But it is highly radioactive, so  it should be worn with caution. Selling price is very high. The probability of occurrence - low. Scientific Organizations, and the Military seem rather interested in these Artefacts for various reasons...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_rusty_kristall">
		<text>Crystal Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_rusty_kristall_s">
		<text>Crystal Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_rusty_kristall">
		<text>the Artefact it is possible to find Rusty hair near to anomaly. He deduces{removes} radiation from an organism of the person, but at the same time opens bleedings so at carrying this artefact it is necessary to be cautious and to not forget about its{his} negative influence. The price average. Interest to an artefact is shown with the scientific organizations, collectors and jewellers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_rusty_sea_urchin">
		<text>Urchin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_rusty_sea_urchin_s">
		<text>Urchin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_rusty_sea_urchin">
		<text>the Artefact is found more often nearby from anomaly with Rusty hair. He deduces{removes} radiation from an organism of the person. However at constant use of this artefact the person has a risk of loss of a plenty of blood. The price high. Interest to an artefact is shown with the scientific organizations, collectors and jewellers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_rusty_thorn">
		<text>Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_rusty_thorn_s">
		<text>Thorn</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_rusty_thorn">
		<text>The end result of the interaction between the Burnt Fuzz anomaly, and a human corpse. The Thorn artefact, when worn on the belt, will continuously pierce, and prick one's side; causing minor lacerations, and bleeding. The upside of this seemingly negative effect, is the artefact's uncanny ability to leach harmful radionucliodes from the body. Although quite widespread throughout the Zone... a keen interest in this artefact is still exhibited by Scientific Organizations, Treasure Collectors, and Exotic Jewellers...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_soul">
		<text>Soul</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_soul_s">
		<text>Soul</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_soul">
		<text>Rare artefact formed in the Springboard anomaly. It is a yellowish-red brilliant concoction of pressed and fancifully curved polymerized residues of plants, soil and bones. Do stalkers is believed that this artifact concluded souls perished in the anomaly of people. When wearing an artifact on your belt, a kind of mysterious way, within a few seconds to fully recover health and stop any bleeding. At the same time deteriorating stamina and resistance to psy-attack monsters telepaths. Also note the stalkers fun fact when you wear on your belt, this artifact is constantly hungry. Selling price is very high. The probability of occurrence - low. Interest in the artifact exhibit scientific organizations, primarily doctors and all sorts of religious cults.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_vyvert">
		<text>Quirk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_vyvert_s">
		<text>Quirk</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_vyvert">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1] +3\n%c[default]Artefact formed in the Vortex anomaly. A compressed, and intricately curvacious remnant of various plant-life, soil and other small objects that were sucked into the Vortex itself... When wearing the artefact on the belt, it tends to decrease the negative effects of gravitational anomalies, such as the Springboard anomaly. The Quirk is relatively easy to find, and as a result it does not demand a very high price. It continues to be studied by Scientists, Ecologists, and the Military in the attempt to determine it's full capabilities...</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Added missing "enc_zone_izomorf_kompas" from russian with google translate aleks1970, chgd to kristal and added short desc 109934 -->
	<string id="af_pkristal">
		<text>Isomorphic Pseudo-Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_izomorf_kristal">
		<text>'Isomorphic' Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_izomorf_kristal_s">
		<text>'Isomorphic' Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_izomorf_kristal_descr">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1] +10\n%c[default]Isomorph. Properties are unknown. But we know only one thing - it is able to neutralize several anomalies, paving the way for the host, while appearing again. It addressed by the anomalies include: hot, Aspic, Fountain, Freezer, bubble, tornado, fog Hearth</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_izomorf_kristal2">
		<text>'Isomorphic' Pseudo-Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_izomorf_kristal2_s">
		<text>'Isomorphic' Pseudo-Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_izomorf_kristal2_descr">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1] +10\n%c[default]Isomorph. Properties are unknown. But we know only one thing - it is able to neutralize several anomalies, paving the way for the host, while appearing again. It addressed by the anomalies include: hot, Aspic, Fountain, Freezer, bubble, tornado, fog Hearth</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Added missing "enc_zone_izomorf_kompas" from russian with google translate aleks1970 -->
	<string id="af_ikompas">
		<text>Isomorphic Compass</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_izomorf_kompas">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1] +10\n%c[default]Isomorph. Properties are unknown. But we know only one thing - it is able to neutralize several anomalies, paving the way for the host, while appearing again. It addressed by the anomalies include: hot, Aspic, Fountain, Freezer, bubble, tornado, fog Hearth</text>
	</string>
	<string id="art_izomorf_kompas1">
		<text>'Isomorphic' Compass</text>
	</string>
	<string id="art_izomorf_kompas1_s">
		<text>'Isomorphic' Compass</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_izomorf_kompas_descr">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1] +10\n%c[default]Isomorph. Properties are unknown. But we know only one thing - it is able to neutralize several anomalies, paving the way for the host, while appearing again. It addressed by the anomalies include: hot, Aspic, Fountain, Freezer, bubble, tornado, fog Hearth</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_izomorf_cactus2">
		<text>'Isomorphic' Cactus</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_izomorf_cactus2_s">
		<text>'Isomorphic' Cactus</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_izomorf_cactus2_descr">
		<text>Unknown Origin; but, for some unexplicable reason, the owner of this 'affected' Cactus is somehow immune from Zombie attacks. Is it possible that through this simple plant, the cure for Zombification could be found?!...</text>
	</string>
	<!--======================================-->
	<!--     ARHARA's ANOMALOUS CAPSULES	  -->
	<!--======================================-->
	<string id="st_caps_mosquito_bald">
		<text>Springboard Capsule</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caps_mosquito_bald_s">
		<text>Springboard</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_caps_mosquito_bald">
		<text>The reasons, and conditions surrounding the formation of this very unique capsule are unknown... It is fully capable of generating the Springboard anomaly upon activation of an enclosed Artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caps_gravi">
		<text>Gravi Capsule</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caps_gravi_s">
		<text>Gravi</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_caps_gravi">
		<text>The reasons, and conditions surrounding the formation of this very unique capsule are unknown... It is fully capable of generating the Gravi anomaly upon activation of an enclosed Artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caps_mincer">
		<text>Whirligig Capsule</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caps_mincer_s">
		<text>Whirligig</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_caps_mincer">
		<text>The reasons, and conditions surrounding the formation of this very unique capsule are unknown... It is fully capable of generating the Whrligig anomaly upon activation of an enclosed Artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caps_electra">
		<text>Elektra Capsule</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caps_electra_s">
		<text>Elektro</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_caps_electra">
		<text>The reasons, and conditions surrounding the formation of this very unique capsule are unknown... It is fully capable of generating the Elektra anomaly upon activation of an enclosed Artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caps_zharka">
		<text>Heat Capsule</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caps_zharka_s">
		<text>Heat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_caps_zharka">
		<text>The reasons, and conditions surrounding the formation of this very unique capsule are unknown... It is fully capable of generating the Heat anomaly upon activation of an enclosed Artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caps_ameba">
		<text>Fruit Punch Capsule</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caps_ameba_s">
		<text>Fruit Punch</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_caps_ameba">
		<text>The reasons, and conditions surrounding the formation of this very unique capsule are unknown... It is fully capable of generating the Fruit Punch anomaly upon activation of an enclosed Artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caps_ice">
		<text>Snow Capsule</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_caps_ice_s">
		<text>Snow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_caps_ice">
		<text>The reasons, and conditions surrounding the formation of this very unique capsule are unknown... It is fully capable of generating the Snow anomaly upon activation of an enclosed Artefact...</text>
	</string>
	<!--======================================-->
	<!--ARTEFACT ACTIVATION (Arhara)		  -->
	<!--======================================-->
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_activation_func">
		<text>Activation Fundamentals</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_activation_basic">
		<text>Under certain conditions, it becomes possible to enclose certain Artefacts in a protective layer, or shell... in order to manipulate them in specific ways that will enable their parent Anomaly to be re-activated on-the-spot. The activated artefact will lose all of it's original properties, and instead will metaphorsisize into another entity altogether... This process releases energy concentrated within an artefact that re-metabolize around the Activation Site. The artefact itself is completely absorbed by the process. Despite the similarity, these anomolous zones are very different in nature from their parental counterparts, whereas the original anomaly regenerates the energy required to sustain it's very existance. In contrast, the fabricated anomaly that is the end result of a successful activation procedure can only last for a very short time... usually only a few short minutes. They will then de-activate, and simply dissipate back into the Zone...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="activation_why">
		<text>Activation Purpose</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_activation_why">
		<text>The root cause of this strange phenomenon is likely to be traced back to the days when the Zone was literally churning with Scientific activity. Laboratories throughout the Zone were conducting similar reverse engineering projects in their attempts to counter the effects of deadly radiation poisoning as a result of the disastrous incident which took place in 2011... At some point, somewhere within the catacombs beneath the Zone, in one of these laboratories, someone discovered the process involved in succesfully activating, or transforming; one form of anomalous energy into another... in this case: an Artefact being able to re-generate into a temporary anomolous field that is a clone of it's parental anomaly...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_activation_practice_title">
		<text>Activation Process</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_activation_practice">
		<text>The Activation process demands that certain conditions be met: It is absolutely necessary to enclose the original Artefact with a special protective shell, and to subsequently manipulate the enclosure in a very specific way... It's correct orientation during the activation process is absolutely essential, and any mistakes will result in a complete failure to activate the Artefact. Other key factors include: adequate space, and correct core temperature of the Artefact in question... Only if these key factors are met with 100% accuracy, will the activation process take place. Some capsules are more easily manipulated than others, which cxan be almost impossible - even in Laboratory conditions...</text>
	</string>
	<!--======================================-->
	<!--     		     MISC.				  -->
	<!--======================================-->
</string_table>
