<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.0.9.9.9.8 added several from bind_det_arts for localization, removed "string_table" - aleks1970 -->

	<!-- 10991.1 -->
	<string id="nm_545x39_izomorf">
		<text>"5.45x39-isomorphic"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nm_545x39_izomorf1">
		<text>"5.45x39-isomorphic-1"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nm_osnova_fotik">
		<text>"Isomorphic basis for f.ap"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nm_linza_fotik">
		<text>"Isomorphic lens for f.ap"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nm_pushka_fotik">
		<text>"Isomorphic gate f.ap"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nm_rukzak_izomorf">
		<text>"Isomorphic backpack"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nm_izom_globus">
		<text>"Isomorphic Globe"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nm_izomorf_kristal">
		<text>"Isomorphic crystal"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nm_ammo_zhekan_izomorf">
		<text>"Jeka-isomorphic"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nm_kaktus_izomorf">
		<text>"Isomorphic cactus"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nm_izomorf_kompas">
		<text>"Isomorphic compass"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nm_wa2000_izomorf">
		<text>"Anomalous walther wa2000"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nm_762x54_izomorf">
		<text>"7.62x54-isomorphic"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nm_psevdokristall">
		<text>"Isomorphic pseudocrystal"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="nm_izomorf_plastilin">
		<text>"Isomorphic plasticine"</text>
	</string>
	<!--  1099.1 end -->
	<string id="af_buliz">
		<text>Cobblestone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_buliz_s">
		<text>Cobblestone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_buliz">
		<text>An Artefact which as a result of an energy collapse, has lost all of it's properties. However, in spite of the absence of any 'special' properties, "Cobblestones" remain interesting to the Scientific Community</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_spirit_1">
		<text>Soul Drops</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_spirit_1_s">
		<text>Drops</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_1">
		<text>This modificate Artefact possesses outstanding properties that increases overall human health, and reduce the effects of radiation. On the other hand, it decreases the endurance of its owner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_spirit_2">
		<text>Fiery Soul</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_spirit_2_s">
		<text>Soul</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_2">
		<text>This mesomodificate artifact has properties similar to Soul Drops, but further reduces the effects of radiation. Like Soul Drops, it also has the negative effect of decreasing the endurance of its owner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_spirit_3">
		<text>Crystal Soul</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_spirit_3_s">
		<text>Soul</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_3">
		<text>This mesomodificate artifact has properties similar to Fiery Soul, but reduces the effects of radiation even further. Like Fiery Soul, it also has the negative effect of decreasing the endurance of its owner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_spirit_4">
		<text>Fervent Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_spirit_4_s">
		<text>Crystal</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_4">
		<text>This hypermodificate artifact has all of the health and radiation benefits of Crystal Soul, but in addition, instead of negatively impacting the owners endurace, it increases it! Truly an 'ultimate' artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_cry_1">
		<text>Elektro Tears</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_cry_1_s">
		<text>Tears</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_cry_1">
		<text>This modificate artifact slightly reduces the effects of radiation for its owner, as well as increases endurance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_cry_2">
		<text>Fire Tears</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_cry_2_s">
		<text>Tears</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_cry_2">
		<text>This mesomodificate artifact inherits only the radiation protection properties from its predecessor, Electro Tears, but increases that protection three-fold.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_cry_3">
		<text>Chimera Tears</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_cry_3_s">
		<text>Tears</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_cry_3">
		<text>This mesomodificate artifact increases the already outstanding radiation protection Fire Tears possessed, but adds the extremely valuable ability to block some psi-emissions. On the other hand, it has the negative effect of increasing bleeding, as well as having an overall detrimental impact on human health in general.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_babka_1">
		<text>Old Glassbeads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_babka_1_s">
		<text>Glassbeads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_babka_1">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+5\n%c[default]This mesomodificate artifact greatly increases the endurance of its owner and generates a gravitational field that bends high velocity objects around it, generally making its owner a more difficult target to hit with weapons fire. However, it is slightly radioactive and increases the voltage of any electrical activity around it, making electrical anomalies even more dangerous.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_babka_2">
		<text>Ancient Glassbeads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_babka_2_s">
		<text>Glassbeads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_babka_2">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+7\n%c[default]This mesomodificate artifact is slightly more radioactive than Old Glassbeads, loses all of its previous ability to enhance endurance, and its gravitational effect is lessened, weakening its significance in affecting weapons fire. However, it does increase general human health, and decreases bleeding.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_babka_3">
		<text>Elder Glassbeads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_babka_3_s">
		<text>Glassbeads</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_babka_3">
		<text>This hypermodificate artifact makes the process of transmuting Old Glassbeads to anything else worth it! It greatly increases its gravitational influence on bullets, making the owner much more impervious to weapons fire, as well as further increasing its positive health properties and its ability to decrease bleeding in its owner. Finally, instead of emitting radiation, it help decrease the effects of radiation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_pudd_1">
		<text>Fire Dummy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_pudd_1_s">
		<text>Dummy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_1">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+2\n%c[default]This mesomodificate artifact, like its predecessor Baby Dummy, protects from burns, but also increases endurance. On the other hand, it also increases electrical shock damage to its owner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_pudd_2">
		<text>Shining Dummy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_pudd_2_s">
		<text>Dummy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_2">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+3\n%c[default]This mesomodificate artifact has the same burn protection as Fire Dummy, but has a greater positive impact on endurance. On the other hand, it also increases electrical shock damage to its owner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_pudd_3">
		<text>Moonshine Dummy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_pudd_3_s">
		<text>Dummy</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_3">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+5\n%c[default]This mesomodificate artifact continues to provide burn protection, just like Shining Dummy, but has an even greater positive effect on endurance. This is balanced by a greater vulnerability to electrical shock damage for its owner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_pudd_4">
		<text>Pudding</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_pudd_4_s">
		<text>Pudding</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_4">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+7\n%c[default]This hypermodificate artifact offers an increase in its burn protection from its predecessor, Moon Dummy, but also instead of creating a vulnerability to electrical shock damage, provides significant protection for it! It still provides some increase in endurance as well, but not nearly as much as before unfortunately.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dik_1">
		<text>Porcupine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dik_1_s">
		<text>Porcupine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_1">
		<text>This mesomodificate artifact, along the lines of its predecesssor Urchin, protects considerably from radiation, but decreases endurance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dik_2">
		<text>Elektro Porcupine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dik_2_s">
		<text>Porcupine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_2">
		<text>This mesomodificate artifact provides nearly the radiation protection of Porcupine, and instead of decreasing, it increases endurance. However, it also makes its owner more vulnerable to electrical shock damage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dik_3">
		<text>Acidic Porcupine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dik_3_s">
		<text>Porcupine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_3">
		<text>This mesomodificate artifact is similar to Electro Purcupine in that it provides some radiation protection, some endurance increase, and weakens its owner to slightly higher electrical shock damage; but it also benefits its owner by decreasing bleeding significantly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dik_4">
		<text>Stone Porcupine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_dik_4_s">
		<text>Porcupine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_4">
		<text>This hypermodificate artifact posseses all of the positive effects of its predecessors, but instead of creating a weakness to electrical shock damage, it provides protection for it to its owner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_kol_1">
		<text>Steel Kolobok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_kol_1_s">
		<text>Kolobok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_1">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+5\n%c[default]This modificate artifact generates a gravitational field, somewhat retarding bullet velocities that enter this field, increasing protection from weapons fire. Also, it improves the human bodys skin, making it tougher and more difficult to tear. Unfortunately - it's radioactive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_kol_2">
		<text>Titan Kolobok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_kol_2_s">
		<text>Kolobok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_2">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+6\n%c[default]This mesomodificate artifact generates a more powerful gravitational field than its predecessor, Steel Kolobok, which has an even more positive impact on weapons fire directed at its owner. It also helps prevent skin from tearing, and protects from burns. Unfortunately - it's more radioactive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_kol_3">
		<text>Diamond Kolobok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_kol_3_s">
		<text>Kolobok</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_3">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+4\n%c[default]This mesomodificate artifact has slightly less of a gravitational field than Titan Kolobok, but still provides some protection from projectiles. Adding to its positive properties of protecting skin tears and adding resistance to burns, it also protects from chemical burns. Unfortunately - it's still radioactive, but not as much as Titan Kolobok was.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_kol_4">
		<text>Sphere</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_kol_4_s">
		<text>Sphere</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_4">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+9\n%c[default]This hypermodificate artifact inherits most of its positive properties from its predecessors in the Kolobok family. It prevents skin tearing, provides very good bullet protection via a gravitational field as powerful as the Titan Kolobok, and protects from burns. Some say it also reduces actual hunger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_armor_1">
		<text>Skin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_armor_1_s">
		<text>Skin</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_1">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+2\n%c[default]This modificate artifact reacts with human skin, reducing susceptibility to high velocity projectiles, such as bullets. It also protects from many forms of chemical burns. It is mildy radioactive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_armor_2">
		<text>Scale</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_armor_2_s">
		<text>Scale</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_2">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+4\n%c[default]This mesomodificate artifact, like its predecessor Skin, forms a barrier on human skin protecting from bullet injury and chemical burns. Scale also contributes to general human health, although as a side effect seems to increase bleeding. It is somewhat radioactive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_armor_3">
		<text>Steel Scale</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_armor_3_s">
		<text>Scale</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_3">
		<text>%c[1,1,1,1]______ %c[255,255,255,255]Radiation %c[255,255,1,1]+3\n%c[default]This mesomodificate artifact inherited the properties of its predecessor's, Scale and Skin, and for the most part has an even more positive effect. Even better, instead of increasing blood loss when injured, it actually decreases bleeding. It is still radioactive however, but slightly less.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_armor_4">
		<text>Controller Scalp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_armor_4_s">
		<text>Scalp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_4">
		<text>This hypermodificate artifact evolves this family of artifacts in a strange way. It is no longer radioactive, still protects from chemical burn and bullet damage, and it still contributes to human health, however, its main benefit now lies in its ability to help its owner resist many forms of psi-emissions! Some also report a severe slackening of appetite, with no negative effects normally associated with lack of food.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_simbion">
		<text>Simbion</text>
	</string>
	<string id="af_simbion_s">
		<text>Simbion</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_simbion">
		<text>This hypermodificate artifact is a unique hybrid modificate, obtained by merging four artifacts and transmutating them. It helps blocks psi-emissions, but on the other hand, it increases the skins susceptibility to tearing, and also promotes blood loss by inhibiting clotting factors. To top it off, this artifact also inhibits the endurance of its owner. Use specifically when attacked by a psi-capable enemy.</text>
	</string>
