<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.0.9.9.9.8 updated to 134, removed "string_table" - aleks1970 -->

	<string id="binoc_tutorial">
		<text>In order to use the binoculars, select it ($$ACTION_wpn_5$$) and press the fire button to use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="binocular">
		<text>Binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_binocular">
		<text>Binocular</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crouch">
		<text>Squats</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crouch_down_tutorial">
		<text>order to bend down low, then ($$ACTION_crouch$$) + (Shift)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="crouch_tutorial">
		<text>In order to sit down, press ($$ACTION_crouch$$). To sit down and press ($$ACTION_crouch$$) + ($$ACTION_accel$$).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hide_weapon">
		<text>Choice weapons</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hide_weapon_tutorial">
		<text>Some stalkers do not want to say, if you poke them with weapons in the face. To hide the weapons, just select the bolt ($$ACTION_wpn_6$$).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jump">
		<text>Jumps</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jump_tutorial">
		<text>Jumping will help you climb into the low hurdles. In order to jump, press ($$ACTION_jump$$).</text>
	</string>
	<string id="move_tutorial">
		<text>Methods movement</text>
	</string>
	<string id="overload">
		<text>Overloading</text>
	</string>
	<string id="overload_tutorial">
		<text>you do not like the truck and carry a few tons can not. The more you are, the more rapidly lose strength. In the end, if you type too much, you can not budge.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radiation">
		<text>Radiation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="radiation_tutorial">
		<text>When a character is in a zone of high radiation background is on a belt or a radioactive artifact, he shows signs of radiation poisoning. At the same time a character begins to decrease health. To remove the effect of radiation damage can take antirads or vodka.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="relation">
		<text>Relations</text>
	</string>
	<string id="relation_tutorial">
		<text>When a player someone helps, then improves the ratio stalker to him and reputation of character in general. If you have a good reputation, then the dealers will sell you products at a discount. If you have a bad reputation, then get ready for high prices.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sleep_tutorial">
		<text>This is a special place to sleep. Here you can sleep, wait overnight, or simply wait for the appointed hour. In order to sleep, you must open the inventory, set the time on the dial in which you want to sleep, and click on the button"relax."After a specified time, the character wakes up. Sometimes he can have dreams.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sprint">
		<text>Acceleration</text>
	</string>
	<string id="sprint_tutorial">
		<text>In some cases the acceleration can save your life. Click walking down ($$ACTION_sprint_toggle$$). During acceleration character runs faster and more jumps, but it quickly gets tired and can not fire a weapon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="starvation_tutorial">
		<text>When a character for a long time not eat, he has a feeling of hunger. When the hunger becomes strong, then slowly decrease the health of the character. In order for the health of the character ceased to decline, we must eat. You can satisfy your hunger by eating a loaf of bread, canned food or a piece of sausage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial">
		<text>Education</text>
	</string>
	<string id="weakness">
		<text>Tired</text>
	</string>
	<string id="weakness_tutorial">
		<text>If you are running either carries a lot of heavy things, you start to tire. If you are tired too much, you will not be able to run or walk for some time. Fortunately, the forces quickly restored, one has only to stand for some time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="weapon">
		<text>Condition weapons</text>
	</string>
	<string id="weapon_tutorial">
		<text>have any weapons there is a parameter of strength. The lower the strength of weapons, the more it sticks. In order to back out of it to shoot, you have to reload (button $$ACTION_wpn_reload$$). The use of the strength of arms is gradually reduced, but several bullets hit him or the blast wave could render it permanently inoperable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wound">
		<text>Open wounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wound_tutorial">
		<text>Spillage on the character is the probability that it will start bleeding. Bleeding - a permanent loss of health. The more serious bleeding (green icon - slight bleeding, red - strong), the more health the character would lose in a unit time. Over time, bleeding go away, but with bandages can stop them instantly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pda_diary_tutorial">
		<text>In CPC dead stalker you find him observing anomalies in the tunnel. It turns out that he discovered the laws governing their appearance. You can read this information in his PDA in the"Diary".</text>
	</string>
