<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.1.0.0.0.0, Removed duplicated string id's: "ui_st_conn_version_differs", "ui_st_conn_cdkey_invalid", "ui_st_conn_cdkey_in_use", "ui_st_conn_cdkey_disabled", "ui_st_conn_new_patch" and "ui_st_conn_no_new_patch",
new subtitles and SMS repair kit text - aleks1970 -->

	<string id="recipi_bpb_scr">
		<text>I finally got this recipe! It was so easy... Just throw the artifact "Grandmother Burer's Beads" into the "Burner" anomaly for five minutes. Success is guaranteed in three out of four cases. You'll get the "Great-grandmother Burer's Beads" artifact. An absolute! That's it... I'm visiting Zahar. It's time to start hunting. I'll leave my notes here. I doubt anyone will ever find this place... Stalker-hunter, Sepator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="dosye_zvez_scr">
		<text>The 'Astrologer' file:\nAstrologer is an ex-Mercenary, whom was sent after the "death truck", to watch for Strelok. This "ride" was planned thoroughly, as well as the crash. Strelok was given a "task" - to kill himself, as well as a photo of Ghost.\nThe meeting with Doc and Fang was arranged as well. Everything was done so he could find the piece of the Monolith. However, it took longer than expected... Measures were taken, and Panther was kidnapped, in order to blackmail Strelok. You know the rest.\nP.S. Obviously, Strelok was used from the beginning, as an instrument for searching out the piece of the Monolith, but he constantly kept messing with the whole ordeal. I feel like that's what provoked the interest of not only the people from the "outside", but someone from the "old" Zone as well.\nI'm sensing a hurry... Immediately take defensive measures. Agent "XYZ"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="stukach_book_scr">
		<text>Informant's Notebook:\nThe mercs have held on to the dough again and have given us only the artifact info...\nFine... At least it's something. "Crystals" might come in handy\nRecipe:\nThrow in the "Fountain" anomaly\n1. Bloodsucker tentacles\n2. "Fireball"\n3. "Medusa"\n4. "Stone flower"\nWait for 5 minutes and you got your free "Crystal", and let the real idiots look for it out there themselves... hehe...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bloknot_pantera_scr">
		<text>Panther's Notebook:\nDon't trust,\nDon't be afraid,\nDon't ask...\nCode to the Warlab door: 25-14-04-56\nCoordinates of the path: 1704, 2154, 4504\nYours truly, Panther</text>
	</string>
	<string id="razved_karta_scr">
		<text>Map Fragments:\nEntrance to the Swamps from Agroprom. It's a pity that the road leads to a radioactive zone. You 'll have to put up with the radiation for about 10m. Better stock up on antirads.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pilot_zapiska_scr">
		<text>To captain Zimin:\nI don't know what made us fly above the station... All 3 helis got stuck right in the middle of an emission.\nOne fell right on the roof of the CNPP, the other got stuck on a pipe and left hanging there. We got lucky, we landed, but it was a rough crash landing. Radiation's off the charts.\nTo get down from here, you need to jump from the heli to a cistern just below... But there's no time left...</text>
	</string>
	<!-- Added revamped repair kit SMS text - aleks1970 -->
	<string id="rec_revampa10_3">
		<text>Received:\n - 25 spare parts for armor ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rec_revampw10_3">
		<text>Received:\n - 5 spare parts for small arms and 15 for the rifle's ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rec_revampa10">
		<text>Received:\n - 10 spare parts for armor ...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rec_revampw10">
		<text>Received:\n - 3 spare parts for small arms and 5 for the rifle's ...</text>
	</string>
	<!-- New text for the onscreen report - aleks1970 -->
	<string id="game_gd_novice">
		<text>Cadet</text>
	</string>
	<string id="game_gd_stalker">
		<text>Advanced</text>
	</string>
	<string id="game_gd_veteran">
		<text>Elite</text>
	</string>
	<string id="game_gd_markedone">
		<text>Marked One</text>
	</string>
	<string id="game_gd_collector">
		<text>Collector Freeplay</text>
	</string>
		<string id="version_scr">
		<text>Version:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="release_scr">
		<text>Release:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="revision_scr">
		<text>Revision:</text>
	</string>
	<string id="network_info">
		<text>Network Info</text>
	</string>