<!-- TB3D 1.0.4e updated to 134-->
<string_table>

	 <string id="esc_akim">
		 <text>Akim</text>
	 </string>

	 <string id="agro_adrenalin">
		 <text>Adrenaline</text>
	 </string>

	 <string id="antizombie">
		 <text>the Antidote</text>
	 </string>

	 <string id="enc_equipment_medi_antizombie">
		 <text>the Newest medical development from the Dharma Initiative. The antidote counteracts the adverse effects of psi-radiation. Taken during the early stages of zombification, it is possible to avoid the transformation. ( two (2) doses must be injected ) ... The only drawback = the price.</text>
	 </string>

	 <string id="mas_outfit_name">
		 <text>Exoskeleton "Stealth"</text>
	 </string>

	 <string id="mas_outfit_description">
		 <text>The newest development to come out of one of the Foreign Secret Laboratories. It is used by Special Forces, Saboteurs, and Scouts for concealment purposes. Details of its first appearance in the Zone are unknown. Used for covert activities when "invisibility" is prudent. Made of polarized metal mesh armor that uses every bit of space for detection and evasion components. The armor itself was fabricated from a composite material different from standard armors. The suit skin has an average thickness of 4 mm. Accomplishes its stealthy edge via multiple scanning devices and wave modifiers that thwart light rays. What the armor lacks in strength it makes up for with guile. The exterior of the suit was crafted from an alloy mesh weaved with prismatic fibers. The resulting surface alters the way light reflects off of it. Operating on similar principles which cause it to blend in to nearby surroundings. This cloaking device merely changes the armor's exterior color (turning it white, for example). While not fool-proof, it has proven to be effective in most situations.</text>
	 </string>

	 <string id="mil_exoskeleton_name">
		 <text>Army Prototype "SKAT15-M"</text>
	 </string>

	 <string id="mil_exoskeleton_description">
		 <text>Prototype of a "s.m.a.r.t." suit of the last generation on the basis of the "SKAT15-M" armour. Provides good protection against psi-influence, and provides built-in health status diagnostics. Increases carrying capacity, however the weight of the suit partially defeats this quality. Special lenses used in the helmet increase the field-of-view, as the helmet's visor encompasses practically 180 degrees, and does not give in to mechanical and chemical influences. There are three slots containing micro-circuits which expand the typical exoskeleton functionalities, but at the expense of increased energy consumption. Not electric, but rather microwave energy, which is created by a particular form of Artefact. Only one prototype suit exists. All records, blueprints, and design documents have been lost.</text>
</string>

	 <string id="mil_exoskeleton_name_add">
		 <text>Modified Army Prototype "SKAT15-M"</text>
	 </string>

	 <string id="mil_exoskeleton_description_add">
		 <text>Modified prototype of the "SKAT15-M" suit with the connected circuit blocks and additional micro-circuits. Has the best available protection against psi-influence, and provides built-in health status diagnostics, as well as an increased carrying capacity. The weight of the suit has been lowered. Consumes much continuous energy, and must be charged approximately every 2 hours of use.</text>
</string> 	

<string id="mil_exoskeleton_description_addr">
<text>The modified prototype suit SCAT-15M, with the activation system modules and attached block apgreydera number 1. Unlike neproapgreydennoy version has a 50% protection against any VIP-impact, advanced built-in parser state of health of the owner, which takes into account the effects of radiation, as well as increased to 70 kg carried weight. \nSKAT-15M - a prototype of a new army suit, the latest generation Manufactured on the basis of SKAT-10. Increases muscle strength of the owner, which makes it possible to carry more weight, but he weighs 26 kg. Used in the manufacture of the latest developments on 'spraying' of some artifacts on the Kevlar skid plates suit, so that has good defensive qualities. In a helmet built a special lens, increasing the angle and the viewing area, the glass which is practically forever and is not susceptible to mechanical or chemical influences. It has one slot for a special set of chips and three slots for blocks of chips that extend the functionality of the exoskeleton, but their activation of the third unit, the suit starts to consume energy, not electrical, and microwave, create some kind of artifacts. This prevented further development of the model. Exist in single copies, drawings and development - have been lost.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_exoskeleton_description_addrs">
<text>The modified prototype suit SCAT-15M, with the activation system modules and attached units apgreydera number 1 and number 2. Unlike neproapgreydennoy version has a 50% protection against any VIP-impact, advanced built-in parser state of health of the owner, which takes into account the effects of radiation, an automated system using energy and increased to 70 kg carried weight. Lack - consumes energy, needs to be recharged in about 2 hours. As the battery is used artifact 'Black Energy'. \nSKAT-15M - a prototype of a new army suit, the last generation, made on the basis of SKAT-10. Increases muscle strength of the owner, which makes it possible to carry more weight, but he weighs 26 kg. Used in the manufacture of the latest developments on 'spraying' of some artifacts on the Kevlar skid plates suit, so that has good defensive qualities. In a helmet built a special lens, increasing the angle and the viewing area, the glass which is practically forever and is not susceptible to mechanical or chemical influences. It has one slot for a special set of chips and three slots for blocks of chips that extend the functionality of the exoskeleton, but their activation of the third unit, the suit starts to consume energy, not electrical, and microwave, create some kind of artifacts. This prevented further development of the model. Exist in single copies, drawings and development - have been lost.</text>
</string>

<string id="doc_1">
<text>Module Activation System</text>
</string>

    <string id="enc_doc">
        <text>Complete set of micro-chips used in the activation of additional modules for the Exoskeleton "SKAT15-M". It is inserted into a special socket within the suit. It is very volatile, but ensures the operation, and subsequent additional functions of the suit itself.</text>
    </string> 
	
<string id="doc_8">
<text>Upgrade Block #1</text>
</string>
    <string id="new_apgreider_1">
        <text>The first set of micro-circuits incorporated within the uniform block, used in the expansion of functionalities for the Exoskeleton "SKAT15-M". They are volatile and unstable. Requires a special slot..</text>
    </string>

<string id="doc_10">
<text>Upgrade Block #2</text>
</string>
    <string id="new_apgreider_2">
        <text>The second set of micro-circuits incorporated within the uniform block, used in the expansion of functionalities for the Exoskeleton "SKAT15-M". They are volatile and unstable. Requires a special slot.</text>
    </string> 

<!--DMX UPGRADE -->

<string id="dmx_skat15_upgrade">
<text>Upgrade Block #3</text>
</string>

<string id="dmx_apgreider_3">
<text>The third set of chips combined into a single unit. They serve to extend the functionality of the Exoskeleton SCAT-15M, after applying upgrades #1 and #2 .. Also, there are new super-lightweight components, which when installed, the weight is reduced to six pounds. The main advantage of the upgrade, however, is that the Armour can now be used without the 'Black Energy' artefact. There is a special slot in order to connect the Upgrade...</text>
</string>


<string id="mil_exoskeleton_description_dmx_upgrade">
<text>The modified prototype suit SCAT-15M, with the activation system modules and attached units apgreydera #1, #2, and  #3. This version has a 50% protection against any VIP-impact, reduced weight suit for six pounds, advanced built-in parser state of health of the owner, which takes into account the effects of radiation, an automated system using energy and increased to 80 kg carried weight. Removed the volatility in a suit, it can be used without the artifact of 'Black Energy'. \nSKAT-15M - a prototype of a new army suit, the last generation, made on the basis of SKAT-10. Increases muscle strength of the owner, which makes it possible to carry more weight. Used in the manufacture of the latest developments on 'spraying' of some artifacts on the Kevlar skid plates suit, so that has good defensive qualities. In a helmet built a special lens, increasing the angle and area of inspection, the glass which is practically forever and is not susceptible to mechanical or chemical influences. There is the model of a single specimen, drawings and development - have been lost.</text>
</string>



</string_table>
