<!-- TB3D 1.0.9.9.5.0, corrected duplicate "id="enc_zone_mushy_bigA" to "id="mushy_bigA" aleks1970 --> 
<string_table>
<string id="af_kristal_zp">
<text>The Gift</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kristal_zp">
<text>This legendary artifact has been found only once in the zone and was sold to scientists for incredible cost. It offers exceptional protection against radiation at the cost of other immunities. If you use this artifact, be beware of these severe side affects.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_kristal_blue">
<text>Aquamarine</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kristal_blue">
<text>%c[1,1,1,1]___%c[255,255,255,255] Backpack Radiation %c[255,255,1,1] +250 \n %c[default]This is an extremely rare mutation of the artifact Crystal and is very radioactive. Its core is thought to be pure platinum of the highest purity. How this structure functions is still not clear, but who cares when you have two kilograms of expensive platinum!  \n Nicknamed "The Fighter" as it protects and gives great defense in combat situations however burn and electric shock immunity are greatly reduced.  If you use this artifact make sue you have the required artifacts to counter the radioactive effects. If not - your going to die a horrible death.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_repei">
<text>Burr</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_repei">
<text>Artifact is the result of genetic experimentation with mutated seeds of 'Hvatalka' plants 'Burning Feathers'. Hardens the skin giving protection from cuts and electric current. Not worth a lot but quite useful.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-indilian">
<text>Indilian</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-indilian">
<text>This extremely rare artifact is also called "Dream Killer" as the users Alpha and Beta brain waves are slowed sufficiently to reduce the effects of Psi attacks. Gives additional protection from attacks of many creatures of the Zone. Its negative effects are a reduced rate of health recovery -  Use only with the artifacts which increase health.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-mushroom">
<text>Mushroom</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-mushroom">
<text>Artifact is a transmutated mushroom formed in the anomaly Springboard. ' Extremely rare. Forms within a radius of 0.3 meters a localised force field which improves immunity to bullet wounds. Artifact also has a range of negative effects such as: weakening of the skin to burns, electric shock and chemicals.  Stalkers on finding this artifact immediately dispose of it because of its negative properties.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_dummy-star_monolith">
<text>Star Monolith</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-star_monolith">
<text>A mysterious artifact. There are two recorded instances of its occurrence in the Zone.......\n* It appeared, according to rumors, when the stalkers of the clan of 'Monolith' entered the center zone. At the altar they preyed, asking the Monolith to gave them a sign of its existence. One night the artifact fell from heaven to earth. The fanatics took this as a sign from the monolith. \n* According to scientists it was formed by the merger of several high altitude air anomalies. \n A very rare item formed only in the area surrounding the Chernobyl nuclear power plant.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-seashell">
<text>Baby Dummy</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-seashell">
<text>Scientists have proclaimed this is a new and rare artifact found by a drunk Stalker near the Bar.  Artifact gives a small improvement in health and chemical protection but lowers bullet resistance.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-djoker">
<text>Joker</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-djoker">
<text>%c[1,1,1,1 ]___%c[255,255,255,255] Backpack Radiation %c[255,255,1,1] +15 \n %c[default] The origin of the artifact is not known and has only been found in the Zone a few times. Artifact gives good protection from impact, but reduces endurance. Radioactive.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-dumbbell">
<text>Kettlebell</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-dumbbell">
<text>This artifact is small and looks like a set of dumbbells - and has the weight to match - 18Kg!. Incredibly strong and dense - can not be cut, melted or pressed. Unknown origin. Improves health and reduces radiation. No negative properties - apart from its large mass.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_dummy-vertyshka">
<text>Pinwheel</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-vertyshka">
<text>The exact origin of this artifact is unknown. Scientists argue that this artifact is formed under the influence of two anomalies - 'Springboard' and 'Elektra'. It is theorised this rare artifact is located in the middle of the anomalies held together by electro-weak unification. The interacting fields make it rotate. Protects from electric shock but there is a reduction in bullet resistance and immunity to radiation...</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-coal">
<text>Coal</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-coal">
<text>Artifact, which appeared in the zone recently. Scientists believe it is formed from nucleosynthesis between Baryonic dark matter and the artifact 'Stone Flower'. Looks like a lump of coal. Artifact gives good protection from psionic waves and raises resistance to radioactive contamination, but with greatly increased fatigue. Make sure you have artifacts that counter the negative effects.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-quill">
<text>Igla</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-quill">
<text>%c[1,1,1,1 ]___%c[255,255,255,255] Backpack Radiation %c[255,255,1,1] +5 \n %c[default] Artifact generated from the radiogenic nuclide of the Artifact "xZs2x4". It protects the skin from burns and media impact. Slightly radioactive.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-wool">
<text>Fire Wool</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-wool">
<text>Rarely found in the Zone and not much is known about how it is created. Provides very good protection from heat sources and attacks from Zone mutants. Explosion and strike immunities are reduced. Demand by scientists.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-bonanza">
<text>Octopus</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-bonanza">
<text>Substance formed by the mutual co-existence of anomalies 'Fountain' and 'Fruit Punch' and Lanthanoid metals. Has a number of positive attributes, and some negative. Was found recently by a Stalker nicknamed Gadget. He picked it up with no protective gloves, only just managing to get it to his backpack before his hand vapourised. On selling the Artifact he was able to get a mechanical prosthetic hand.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-mercury_ball">
<text>Mercury Ball</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-mercury_ball">
<text>%c[1,1,1,1 ]___%c[255,255,255,255] Bacpack Radiation %c[255,255,1,1] +20 \n %c[default] Artifact often can be found in Radioactive areas. Increases stamina but has negative radiation attributes.  The main central core is surrounded by spinning smaller mercury balls. Special gloves are recommended for handling due to its radiation and high thermal energy. Scientists have discovered that some of the artifact actually consists of of the mercury isotope Hg-194, and can be used to manufacture medicinal drugs and vaccines for a wide varity of dangerous Zone diseases.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-bezi">
<text>Burning Leaves</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-bezi">
<text>Scientists believe that this new mutation belongs to the genus family of nettles. First found by an unknown Stalker on a Surveying Expedition deep into the Zone. Synthetic hybrids have been the focus of experiments in the X-18 and X-16 laboratories. Able to reject chemical components and reduces bleeding by speeding up blood clotting.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-glow">
<text>Glow</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-glow">
<text>Artifact formed in the anomaly 'Elektra' from a variety of metal objects and alloys. The high energy states of outer valence electrons causes a localised luminescence. After detailed study, researchers found that the artifact actually produces electricity in small amounts. Using the Artifact causes the skin to soften - increasing the risk of bleeding out when cut. Resistance to radioactive contamination is lowered but there is increased resistance to burns.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_dummy-node">
<text>The Knot</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-node">
<text>%c[1,1,1,1 ]___%c[255,255,255,255] Backpack Radiation %c[255,255,1,1] +7 \n %c[default]Scientists have been trying to unravel the mystery of this artifact. Stronger than titanium and harder than diamond but weighs less than a kilogram. Creates a slight protective field, distorting the trajectory of bullets. Adverse Effects - radioactive and reduces the resistance to impact injuries.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_kosi">
<text>Witch Spit</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-kosi">
<text>Artifact formed by the combination of three anomalies - 'The Fountain,' 'Heat' and 'Fruit Punch'. Extremely rare. Scientists and researchers still do not fully understand this artifact, but it's obvious that in order to be created the fusing of the 3 anomalies must of released an enormous amount of energy. Using this artifact increases the body's metabolism giving greater endurance and quicker blood clotting. Higher metabolism causes higher body temperature forcing body to the skins surface and a greater vulnerability to wounds.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-kournikova">
<text>Kournikova</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-kournikova">
<text>%c[1,1,1,1 ]___%c[1,1,1,255] Longing for a real Zone Woman.....100% \n %c[default]An artifact of absolute beauty and wonder. Many STALKERS scour the Zone looking for this rare item - but there's only one.  The presence of this artifact raises blood pressure significantly which assists in expelling chemical and radioactive agents.  The drawback is that the user quickly tires. Slightly radioactive and hot to touch.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_gold">
<text>Gold</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_gold">
<text>Very valuable in the Zone. Sought after for the repair of circuit boards.  Gold can be beaten thin enough to become translucent. Such semi-transparent sheets also strongly reflect infrared light, making it useful as infrared (radiant heat) shields in visors of heat-resistant suits.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_xzs2x4">
<text>xZs-2x4</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_xzs2x4">
<text>Discovered by a Zone Scientist years ago.  He was so excited that he could not think of an appropriate name and by default it has only its Scientific designator. This extremely rare artifact will protect from the attacks of many creatures of the Zone. Its main drawback is less protection from bullets.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_hawking">
<text>Hawking K2</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_hawking">
<text>Theoretical Physicists speculate that this artifact is the result of a micro-miniture roaming balck hole captured in the Chernobyl Explosion gravity well and amalgamatedwith stray heavy elements under unusual particle conditions. Impossibly rare and extremely dense. Has a localised effect of bending the path fast moving projectiles away from the user - including bullets and radiation..</text>
</string>

<string id="af_zhadum">
<text>Z'ha'dum</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af_zhadum">
<text>A strange artifact that will destroy your soul if misused.  Rumor has it that some meteorites from the outer rim made it to earth and seeded micro organisms in a host artifact near Chernobyl. Gives exceptional telepathic immunity but will quickly suck the life force from you.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_konishi">
<text>Konishi artifact</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_konishi">
<text> Very, very rare. Rumors are that this artifact absorbs and destroys harmful energy in direct violation of conservation of energy. Unfortunately energy is also drawn from the person wearing this artifact giving them an insatiable appetite. </text>
</string>

<string id="af_element_zero">
<text>Element Zero</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_element_zero">
<text> Element Zero is a rare material that, when subjected to an electrical current, releases dark energy which can be manipulated into a mass effect field, raising or lowering the mass of all objects within that field. A positive current increases mass, a negative current decreases it. Zone Scientists hope to some day manipulate gravity with this rare artifact. Slightly radioactive. </text>
</string>

<string id="af_star_paradox">
<text>Star Paradox</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_star_paradox">
<text> A true enigma of Physics. How it does it baffles the Zone Scientists but this artifact has no negative attributes and many advantages. </text>
</string>

<string id="mushy_bigA">
<text>UV Mushroom</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_mushy_bigA">
<text> An unusually colored and textured Mushroom.  Zone rumors are that the color is due to focused high energy Ultraviolet rays.  Some very rare artifacts apparently can do this and have a focal length of around 5 to 10m. A trader in the Army Warehouses may be interested in buying this Mushroom. </text>
</string>

<string id="mushy_bigB">
<text>Radiated Mushroom</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_mushy_bigB">
<text> For some reason this Mushroom has very high levels of radiation. The ability of mushrooms to absorb nearby heavy metals, including those that are radioactive could be the reason behind this.  Don't carry these for too long, they are slightly radioactive after all!  Scientists are interested in these curiosities of the zone. </text>
</string>

<string id="mushy_bigC">
<text>Fly Mushroom</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_mushy_bigC">
<text> A variation of the Amanita muscaria commonly known as the fly agaric. Poisonous and psychoactive - an old Stalker use to brew and eat these in an attempt to negate the harmful affects of artifacts.  Sid may be interested in buying these.</text>
</string>

<string id="mushy_bigD">
<text>Bluetop</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_mushy_bigD">
<text> Rare chromophores give this Mushroom its striking light blue color - probably caused from the absorbsion of heavy metals like Niobium. The Blue hue was the favorite color of some guy called the "Collector". This Mushroom's color is highly sought after by Clear Sky traders and is used in production of their Body Armor and suits - hence the unique faction color. </text>
</string>

<string id="mushy_bigE">
<text>Flouro Mushroom</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_mushy_bigE">
<text> An irradiated mutation of the Russula fragilis. Dangerous heavy metals have enhanced this Mushroom's striking color. These heavy metals are only found in human excrement accumulated in the body from travels deep into the zone.  Did someone leave something else around here?.  </text>
</string>

<string id="mushy_bigF">
<text>Death Cap</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_mushy_bigF">
<text> Mutated Amanita phalloides is a deadly poisonous Mushroom. Ideal to feed to your enemies. Is normally found deep in the Zone. This one must have grown from spores transferred in the soles of boots. </text>
</string>

<string id="mushy_bigG">
<text>Russula Sanguinaria</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_mushy_bigG">
<text> Commonly known as the bloody brittlegill, is a strikingly colored mushroom. Poisonous when eaten raw. Sought after, this Mushroom is not only scarce but it contains rare heavy elements that are only found in a few small areas of the Zone. Only one "secret" Trader in the Zone will buy this from you but you will need to find him .....or her </text>
</string>

<string id="mushy_bigH">
<text>Caesier's_mushroom</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_mushy_bigH">
<text> Caesier was well traveled and got to know the Collector quite well. Some say that the Collector passed on his Zone secrets before he disapeared and Caesier could be the carrier of the secrets. The mere existence of this unique Mushroom supports this theory as the Collector was an expert in this area. Knowing how the Collector left cryptic clues all over the Zone, perhaps Caesier did the same?....... \n  The Caesier Mushroom has a very hard stem which only the sharpest knifes could possibly carve. Make sure you don't loose this item - it may come in handy latter on. </text>
</string>

<string id="mushy_small">
<text>Dark Knight</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_mushy_small">
<text> The Dark Knight was a favourite Mushroom of the Collector.  If he's left this lying around, you never know what else you might find nearby.  </text>
</string>

</string_table>