<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.0.9.9.9.8, removed "string_table" - aleks1970  -->

<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_1">
<text>Set me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_11">
<text>Hmm. And what kind of job? Something you want? Or maybe already found? I've heard here is full of goodness ...</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_111">
<text>Sorry, I can not tell, and even once.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_1111">
<text>Yes you wait to run away. Run into more ... And I found? I'm also here not just drag.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_11111">
<text>This is my business, what I found.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_11112">
<text>Found documents  X-18, bartender promised to pay well.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_112">
<text>No, nothing found.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2">
<text>I do not know how here skidded to get out of here as soon as possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21">
<text>not find anything interesting coincidence? They say you can find information about the experiments. Paid handsomely for it ...</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_211">
<text>No, I could not find.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2111">
<text>Yes? .. And if you think twice? Hiding from me anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21111">
<text>No.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21112">
<text>What questions?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21113">
<text>you threatening me?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_212">
<text>To hell with all this information, I've barely stayed alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2121">
<text>Well, Run. Suddenly you find that - I am far ...</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_25">
<text>Listen, buddy, I'm in this same zone passed through the fire, anomalies and monsters and still alive, as you see! So do not tell me what to say and what not. I came for the documents. And without them, I will not. If they join you, then I advise you to give them away, otherwise you will stay in this hole forever! Truncating?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_251">
<text>clear.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2511">
<text>If you're lying to me - you will have problems if you thought of something - you will have problems if you give me podsunesh some disgusting - you will have problems. In short, you have one big problem - and you need a try to solve it! And now again to blunt: you find documents?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2521">
<text>That's good, and next time choose expressions. Now go. Suddenly you find that - I am far ...</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_253">
<text>conversation is over, get out of the way.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_26">
<text>I have no documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_271">
<text>So it is better, dear. And now give me all the information that I found. All to one document. And do not start to joke with me - otherwise it will be your last joke ...</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_51">
<text>Wait, I tell you! I'm in this hole is not just drag. Do not play the fool Go on, he found. Share, if that ...</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_511">
<text>Share nothing I do not intend to.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_5111">
<text>Well, well, vali ... Yes, that's only one piece of advice - watch your feet, not spotknis, stalker!</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_512">
<text>you threatening me?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_5121">
<text>Okay, okay you do not boil ... Just curious, but you just behind the barrel! No more questioning. Just be careful, and all.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_61">
<text>Documents means ... This is exactly for what I came to your account. And now you tell me will you give them to flee, he fled. Do you understand me?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_6111">
<text>Come on, say something.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_6121">
<text>Listen, buddy, do not bother me. Let's agree. I normally dumps you, you will not regret.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_6131">
<text>Listen, I really need these documents. Let's see, what have you got - I think we agree ...</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8011">
<text>dark here, no shit in sight. Byurery around ... And why did I agree? You're how I got here?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8021">
<text>Go your way, stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8031">
<text>I hate it when the conversation is interrupted. In short, I came for important documents. If you find something - Go on, otherwise you will have problems. If you did not find - and not take the piss off my time.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8041">
<text>I hate it when the conversation is interrupted! Submit papers, if you do not want to stay here forever.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_9">
<text> I Shall consider. </text>
</string>