<!--?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- TB3D 1.0.9.9.9.8 added ALD-Weapons pack description, glow grenades, aleks1970 edits, removed "string_table" - aleks1970  -->

	<!-- WEAPON ADDITIONS -->
<string id="enc_arsenal_vepr12">
<text>Boar-12 'Hammer'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_vepr12_s">
<text>Boar-12</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_vepr12_descr">
<text>Boar-12 is a relatively new development from the factory "Hammer" and was created as a direct competitor is very popular in Russia guns Sayga-12S/12K series.\nBasis of the Boar-12 gun is the time-tested design of the RPK machine-gun(also produced at the factory hammer).\nThe main purpose of the Boar-12 is as a sport weapon(practice fire by the rules of IPSC), as well as defense and home security activity.\nBoar-12 is a good weapon for law enforcement agents.\n • Ammunition:\n • 12x70 Buckshot,\n • 12x70 Tungsten Buckshot,\n • 12x76 Slug,\n • 12x76 Dart. </text>
</string>
<string id="wpn_ump45_Taktik">
<text>HK UMP-45 'Taktikal'</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn_ump45_Taktik_s">
<text>HK UMP-45</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn_ump45_Taktikal">
<text>• Ammunition: .45 ACP FMJ, .45 ACP Hydro-Shok\n • Weight: 2.5 kg\n • Magazine Capacity: 30+1 rounds\n The UMP "Taktikal" is a blowback-operated , magazine-fed submachine gun with integrated silencer and eotech scope, firing from a closed bolt.\n As originally designed, the UMP is chambered for larger cartridges and magazines than other submachine guns like the MP5,\nto provide more stopping power against unarmored targets (with a slightly lower effective range) than the 9x19mm MP5 provides.\nA larger cartridge produces more recoil, and makes control more difficult in fully automatic firing. To mitigate this, is equiped with larger magazine.\nThe cyclic rate of fire was improved to 700 rounds/min (600 rounds/min for the UMP45).</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn_fn2000_paratrooper">
<text>FN2000 'Marine'</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn_fn2000_paratrooper_s">
<text>FN2000</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn_fn2000_paratrooper">
<text>• Ammunition: 9x39mm PAB9, SP-5 SP-6, 9x39 isomorphic\n • a scope (x8.0)\n • effective range of 600m\n • Effective range 800 m\n • rate of 890/m\n • Magazine capacity 30 rounds\n • rifle grenade M209\n • integrated silencer for caliber 9x39 mm\nGun is created on the base-automatic grenade launcher Belgian Fabrique Nationale Herstal F2000 on request for groups of officers SPN Navy.\nIn the manufacture of parts used various artifacts, which significantly increased the performance characteristics of weapons.\nA small party of these complexes was found at the crash site of a military helicopter. How does this instance got Sidor,\nas well as what happened to the rest of the trunks of the party is absolutely not clear, but in the zone behind them is a real hunt. </text>
</string>
	<!-- UNIQUE WEAPON ADDITIONS -->
<string id="enc_weapons1_VSS_Taktikal">
<text>VSS Vintorez 'Tactical'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_VSS_Taktikal_s">
<text>VSS Vintorez</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn_VSS_Taktikal">
<text>Tactical Vintorez with Eeotech red dot colimerator and posability to attach\n • Elcan Digital Hunting scope.</text>
</string>
	<!-- ATTACHMENTS -->
	<!-- BLADES -->
	<!-- SCOPES -->
<string id="wpn-scope_elcan">
<text>ELCAN Digital hunting scope</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-scope_elcan_s">
<text>ELCAN</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon_scope_elcan">
<text>This particular model utilizes a computerized scope system with variable zoom factor... </text>
</string>
<string id="ars-scope_m2">
<text>PSO-3</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-scope_m2_s">
<text>PSO-3</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_scope_m2">
<text>Reticle high multiplicity JI-3.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_scope_m1">
<text>POSP 3-9x42V Optical sight</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_scope_m1_s">
<text>POSP 3-9x42V</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_scope_m1_descr">
<text>POSP 3-9x42V relates to an optical sight, which can be used in the dark with built-in backlight.\nThe design of this model provides for adjustment of lateral and angular corrections using flywheels.\nThe alternating increase and rangefinder modernized grid allows POSP 3-9x42V to easily determine the distance to the object under observation.\nTightness is ensured by the sight of nitrogen, which is filled with the internal part of the body, it also prevents the formation of moisture on the lenses inside,\nand possible corrosion of metal components. Mount POSP 3-9x42V standard, the type of "dovetail" mounting diameter as the cylindrical part is 1 inch.\nDesigned for use on the SVU-AS sniper rifle. </text>
</string>
	<!-- AMMUNITION -->
	<!-- GLOWING GRENADES -->
<string id="fosfor_grenade_g">
<text>AN-M83G Green Phosphor</text>
</string>
<string id="fosfor_grenade_r">
<text>AN-M83R Red Phosphor</text>
</string>
<string id="fosfor_grenade_b">
<text>AN-M83B Blue Phosphor</text>
</string>
<string id="fosfor_grenade_y">
<text>AN-M83Y Yellow Phosphor</text>
</string>
<string id="fosfor_grenade_descr">
<text>Military Spec. Ops. AN-M83 Phosphor grenades.\n• lighting range: - 10 meters\n• lighting time: - around 1 minute\nThis special model is based on the AN-M83 HC white smoke hand grenade.\n Grenade body is made mostly from fiberglass and contains filler with chemical agents which are needed to obtain glowing light effect in various colors based on the contained reagent after the grenade ignition.\nThere are four colors of this version:\n• Military AN-M83R - 'red'\n• Military AN-M83B - 'blue'\n• Military AN-M83G - 'green'\n• Military AN-M83Y - 'yellow'\nAll versions have problems with the stability and may become activated if dropped or impacted!</text>
</string>
	<!-- 20:05 16.11.2014 -->
