	<!-- TB3D 1.0.9.9.9.8 -->
	 <string id="esc_direction_fire">
		 <text>Remain steady ... we attack strictly on my command.</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="esc_fanat_victory">
		 <text>We have won!!! Loot the bodies, and restock your supplies. Marked One, come here, we must have a word in private ...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="esc_return_dv">
		 <text>Hello, Marked One, glad that see that you are alive, and have come here to see us. Drop in, we will chat. We have some business to attend to ...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="esc_tutorial_end">
		 <text>Excellent, the task is complete. Consider yourself welcome here ...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="esc_wolf_thanks">
		 <text>Marked One, now that you have checked out with the Trader, we can do business together ... come here, I want to speak with you ...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="escape_fox_quest">
		 <text>Marked One ... about Strelok. There is a S.T.A.L.K.E.R. named Fox, who has just returned from a deep raid into the Zone. He's asking for help, as he has some vicious dogs on his tail. Says that he won't be able to hold out for long. He may have some useful information about Strelok. Go help him ... I've uploaded his co-ordinates ...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="escape_stalker_death">
		 <text>Fuck you, Marked One. Though it is not your fault, some Rookies were killed in vain ... Anyhow - after you have been cleared by the Trader, come back, we will talk then ...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="escape_stalker_helped">
		 <text>Good work, Marked One. If you continue like this, you will make many friends here in the Zone. Come here ... we will talk.</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="escape_stalker_killed">
		 <text>Well, Marked One, you're quite vain, aren't you?! Anyhow, you have passed the Trader's test, and so now Wolf is interested in conducting some business with you ...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="info_esc_give_agroprom_task">
		 <text>The Military have dug up something near the Scientific Research Institute at Agaprom. I am quite interested to learn more about it, and you probably should be too. Get the information and deliver it to the Barman at the 100*Rads in the old factory town of Rostok in the North.</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tips_esc_trader_about_anomalies">
		 <text>Use bolts to determine the location of anomolies ... it could save your life!!!</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tips_esc_trader_about_pda">
		 <text> Press the "Contacts" button in your PDA. Those people within a 250 meter radius with PDA's of their own will show up on your mini-map. Be careful though ... most Bandits don't own PDA's, so they may not be so easily detected.</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tips_esc_trader_activate_map">
		 <text>'$$ACTION_MAP$$'</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tips_esc_trader_activate_pda">
		 <text>'$$ACTION_ACTIVE_JOBS$$'</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tips_esc_trader_how_to_talk">
		 <text>'$$ACTION_USE$$'</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tips_esc_trader_quest_1">
		 <text>Find the Artefact located on the map, and bring to the Trader ...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tutorial_flash_anomaly_alarm">
		 <text>Marked One, be very cautious ... Next time ... it could be you instead!!!</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tutorial_trader_give_medikit">
		 <text>Give the first-Aid kit to this moron ...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tutorial_trader_look_vagon">
		 <text>Marked One!!! To hell with him, and with the Artefact. Later, you can bring it to me. Get to a carriage in the middle of the road, and help my men!!!! Some morons opened fire upon a Helicopter. I have sent you the co-ordinates ...</text>
	 </string>
	 <string id="tutorial_trader_search_corpses">
		 <text>Search corpses, as there may be something useful on them ...</text>
	 </string>
