<!-- TB3D 1.0.9.9.9.8 -->
	<string id="bar_arena_actor_afraid">
		<text>Fight is cancelled. The challenger was frightened and did not come out to the ring.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_10">
		<text>Has passed 10 seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_20">
		<text>Has passed 20 seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_30">
		<text>Has passed 30 seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_40">
		<text>Has passed 40 seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_50">
		<text>Has passed 50 seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_60">
		<text>there Has passed minute!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_70">
		<text>there Has passed minute and 10 seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_80">
		<text>there Has passed minute and 20 seconds!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_90">
		<text>Has passed one and a half minute!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_begin">
		<text>Fight has begun!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_bloodsucker">
		<text>Attention! Attention! Soon in arena new fight will be started! In the left corner of arena blood-thirsty and eternally hungry bloodsucker! In the right corner of arena... The person? Yes, the person! All name its Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_burer">
		<text>Attention! Attention! Soon in arena new fight will be started! In the left corner of arena, he knows a kung fu, he is able to bend spoons, it is a burer! In the right corner of arena the hero, whose search never will end! All name its Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_dead">
		<text>So! The opponent has killed the challenger. Here so number!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_lose">
		<text>So! The challenger has killed the opponent, but was not in time during time and has lost!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_pseudodog">
		<text>Attention! Attention! Soon in arena new fight will be started! In the left corner of arena white, fluffy, but improbably malicious pseudo-dog! In the right corner of arena come from anywhere, going anywhere. All name its Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_savage">
		<text>Attention! Attention! Soon in arena new fight will be started! In the left corner of arena, you know it, you love it. And he hates you. It is the Animal! In the right corner of arena still live Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_snork">
		<text>Attention! Attention! Soon in arena new fight will be started! In the left corner of arena the expert on oriental combat sports and eutrophy a snork! In the right corner of arena the person without the past. All name its Marked One!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_timeout">
		<text>Time left! The challenger has lost, but still struggles for life!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_arena_fight_victory">
		<text>So! The challenger has had time to kill the opponent and has won!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_attack">
		<text>As you wish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_attract_actor">
		<text>Stalker, friend! I beg, do not leave, help us! Anarchists have brought down our helicopter and now will finish us. We have wounded men, your help is necessary to us!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_heli_down">
		<text>He-he, that's all. There is no your helicopter! Now get those governmental rats!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_start_heli">
		<text>Well everything, the Wolfhound, you have got into a mess. The military helicopter here flies. Now they you, as puppies!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_escape">
		<text>Professor has run away! Urgently all in a pursuit of Kruglov! He could not go far.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_hit">
		<text>Marked One, help me!!! I'm hit!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_1">
		<text>You will manage, a jackal. At first school finish, and you will put ultimatums then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_2">
		<text>If you will attack, I will destroy the information. Figs to you, instead of my works.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_3">
		<text>If you do not want me to destroy the results of research - steer clear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_4">
		<text>Wolfhound, withdraw the dogs while tails have not peeled!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_attack">
		<text>Everything, conversations are ended. Shooting begins.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_attack_attract_actor">
		<text>This is business. Together we will finish these governmental rats.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_attack_spy">
		<text>Marked One. You will pay for this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_chase">
		<text>They follow us?! Marked One, stop them!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_spam_1">
		<text>You are in short, a scientific blockhead. Give me results, or you will leave from here in a plastic bag.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_spam_2">
		<text>Kruglov, I might not know karate, but I do know crazy. Want to quiz me on it? Or will you give the information?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_spam_3">
		<text>Professor, you're a clever person. Give the information and be ready to go on all fours.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_freedom_spam_4">
		<text>Kruglov, you yet have not understood?! We have brought down your fucking helicopter and that information which you carry is necessary to us. After you will give it to us, can bring down with the children. It is your last chance to get out from here, give the flash card and run.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_psih_come">
		<text>Urgently come here! Near the Radar my children have caught the mad stalker, now we try to interrogate him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_dolg_1_hit">
		<text>Marked One, are you crazy? Immediately stop shooting! This is an order!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_dolg_2_hit">
		<text>Marked One, immediately stop shooting! If you disobey the order, you're a corpse!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_dolg_3_hit">
		<text>Marked One. For infringement of the code of "Duty" you are expelled from the grouping. Henceforth you're our enemy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_dolg_kill">
		<text>Marked One, you have disobeyed the order! Now you're a corpse! "Duty" does not forgive!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_nodolg_1_hit">
		<text>Stop shooting! In territory of "Duty" shooting is forbidden! Disobeyed will be punished!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_nodolg_2_hit">
		<text>Attention! For infringement of the law, a use of weapons in territory of "Duty", the Marked One is declared to be a criminal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_territory_nodolg_kill">
		<text>Attention! The murderer is found out! The order all being in "Duty" territory! Urgently destroy the murderer!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rostok_kruglov_spam_1">
		<text>Stalker, help! We were attacked by mercenaries, half of ours was lost. Help us, we will return the favour.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rostok_kruglov_spam_2">
		<text>Help us to make the way through an ambush near factory, I to you have sent co-ordinates. Be careful, Wolfhound is with bandits near the helicopter.</text>
	</string>