<!-- TB3D 1.0.5e 134 and AMK2-->

<string id="agr_find_ghost_descr">
<text>I have learned that one of the group's name is Ghost. At least some clue for now ... If I can find Ghost, perhaps I can find information on Strelok ...</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_journal_cache">
<text>I found a USB stick, which Strelok's group used as a logbook of sorts. Information was scarce, but there was this: - Strelok's group consisted of at least 2 more members besides himself: Ghost and Fang. There was also reference to a mutual friend, but whether he actually belonged to the group is unknown. But he did, in fact, provide substantial assistance to the group nonetheless. According to Specter ... Fang died when they were ambushed. Only one person left, who knows Strelok directly - Ghost. Finally ... something concrete. Judging from the correspondence between them. I need to look further North .. and so I shall ...</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_journal_krot">
<text>Meeting up with Mole was a productive move. Apparently, the group has a hiding place somewhere in the catacombs beneath the Agroprom Research Institute. I need to go there, and seek it out. I know not what horrors await me there ... or if I will find anything at all worthwhile. But, I have to look ... I must .. it is the only way.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_krot_secret_info">
<text>Mole: This is what I was told: .. Go down the spiral staircase to a room filled with columns. Then around to the right to the exit. Go into a big room full of vats, and pipes along the ceiling. From there, go down to the second exit, which takes you into another tunnel. Turn left. At the end of this course there will be an opening on the right. There's a small room there ... cross through it, and turn right again. Walk along this corridor until, on the left wall you will see something written near a hatch with a ladder going upward ... This is the entrance to Strelok's hiding place ...</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_krot_secret_info_name">
<text>Strelok's Cache</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_military_case">
<text>For Official Use Only: Project Manager TRUE Colonel SBU Kruchelnikovu VM From the head of the Search-2, Captain Maksimenko DF Memorandum ...\nOur team of 3 investigators and the Special Forces branch of the SBU in the period from 12.05.2012 to 25.05.2012 conducted a survey of the premises of the former research institute of agriculture in radioactively-contaminated soils SRI 'Agroprom. Most of the equipment and documents have disappeared in an unknown direction, but even the little that is found, the following conclusions: from 2005 to 2008 the Institute to research on their profile was not engaged. All the results of his work received by the Ministry of Agriculture, were fabricated. At the same time, getting under the state program funding, equipment and supplies guidance Research Institute, represented by Dr. Peter Strizh Danilovich, the fake invoices forwards all this into some kind of laboratory X-18 under the pretext of conducting experiments in time farm of the institute. Apparently, using the code name taken from a group of people passing on the case, because the laboratory with similar numbers in our database. Based on an analysis of documents found can be assumed that it is within an hour's drive from the Institute Agroprom. Most probably we are talking about deep conspiratorial lab so I propose to connect to its search our research department. What did this lab to understand the available information does not seem possible. In the found documents we are talking about a notorious professor Chubko and mentions a certain group. It is my deep conviction that this time we found the end of the thread as the research department will be something to take. Annex zipped file with the overhead transmission supplies and equipment in some time farm of the institute and an excerpt from the correspondence Strizh Chubko.\n Captain Maksimenko DF 26/05/2012 Prof. Chubko VM Head of Research Agroprom Doctor of Agricultural Sciences Strizh PD Hello, Vadim Mikhailovich ...\nAs we agreed, I refer to our guinea farm next batch of supplies and equipment for your much-needed for agricultural experiments. Financing of the experiments I conducted as a full-scale experiments on the topics of our institute, so that the ministry will be no problems. How are the experiments? I am still under the impression that you showed me last time.\n Sincerely yours, PD Swift D. \nYes. Mr. Swift PD Much obliged, Petr Danilovich, all received. My guys are delighted with the laser spectrometer, if not for you, I would have punched through their long this model. But the Ministry of Agriculture, of course, be grateful to get our results, the old man laugh. Experiments are their course and what you saw last time, pales in comparison with what we have achieved. Rides more often - always glad to see you. The more so by car to our guinea economy, as you put it, you go an hour, not more. Yes, I forgot, I have news for you - the following Monday, I will discuss your candidacy with the Group. I think they will support me. \nSincerely, Prof.. Chubko VM Prof. Chubko VM Head of Research Agroprom \nDoctor of Agricultural Sciences Strizh PD Vadim Mikhailovich, thank you for your trust. I am touched and try to justify it. Participate in such an experiment, I think every scientist dreams, and if I take a group, I'll be very happy. Sincerely yours, PD Swift P.S. I knocked at the Ministry two newest Japanese broadband oscilloscope and transferred them to you from the first convenient opportunity ...</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_military_case_name">
<text>Investigative Report</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_nii_security_plan">
<text>This stolen schematic outlines all foot patrols, guard posts, and sniper towers throughout the Agroprom Research Facility. The third floor of the Institute Headquarters is the last known location of the documents you are looking for. They are sealed inside of a bullet/fire-proof briefcase. You must be extremely careful ... During the daytime, the entire area is under constant surveilance. At night, there are only a few light patrols. At precisely 2300hrs there is a shift changeover, when the main building will be practically empty. To access the area by means of the main gate would be absolute suicide. The only safe way ... the smart way ... is through the catacombs ..</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_nii_security_plan_name">
<text>A detailed overhead security schematic of the Agroprom Research Institute</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_rats_n_soldiers_text">
<text>Military delinquents that have been sent into the sewers.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_task_case">
<text>Trader: As soon as you have retrieved the Military Documents inside of the secure briefcase from the Agroprom Institute ... you must take them to the Barkeep at the 100 Rads bar in the former factory town of Rostock. He will be awaiting your arrival ...</text>
</string>

<string id="article_agr_krot_sos">
<text>HELP!! .. the Military have us cornered ... surrounded here .. anyone who can hear this ... Help me!!</text>
</string>

<string id="article_agr_krot_sos_name">
<text>Meeting with Mole</text>
</string>

<string id="article_agr_krot_sos1">
<text>Mole: Help us!! .. Please help us get through this!!...</text>
</string>

<string id="st_operation_agroprom">
<text>Operation Agroprom</text>
</string>

<string id="storyline_gunslinger_flash_info">
<text>Retrieved from Ghost's PDA: I have terrible news. Fang is dead. We waited in the village near the warehouses for a very long time. Three S.T.A.L.K.E.R.s came ... Canine sensed them somehow .. the way he can sometimes. The first two were easily dealt with, but the third turned out to be a bit smarter than his comrades. He set himself up with a Vintorez some 100 meters away from us ... He took Fang out with a single shot ... It was a good shot too .. straight between the eyes!!! I'll never know exactly who ordered the assasination, but we must be careful. I got a look at him afterwards, as he slinked away in the dark. It was one of the Mercenaries. He had a large scar on his face. His eyes glowed as if they were on fire. Who was he?! Who hired him?, and why?! I will try to find out. For both our sakes. Be alert, my friend, and Good Luck. You must continue North .. make it to the Center of the Zone ... I will try to make it there too ... to meet you ... be careful Strelok ... strange things are afoot ... \nGhost</text>
</string>
